Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone. Am I audible? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think,
Krish NAik: Let's wait 2-3 minutes for others also.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, today, we'll be starting the multimodal ride project, okay? So, today's class is all about setup, so pretty much practical thing. First, we'll be doing the testing in GPU.
Krish NAik: sorry, first CPU in my local Mac I'll be doing, so similarly, you guys can do it in your own CPUs. But, just be sure you have a lot of RAM.
Krish NAik: at least, like, 32 gigs. If you don't have 32 gigs, then the local testing guys can skip it, okay? And then directly, like, we'll be switching to Lightning AI, and then I'll be setting up the environment.
Krish NAik: That will be. The last multimodal question, I have question. Okay, yeah, Rajat, you can ask your question, no issues. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Let's wait for 5… I think, 4 to 5 minutes more, and then we will start. In the meantime, let me start sharing my screen. Rajat, you can type it now. Okay, so this is… let's start.
Krish NAik: Yeah, Rajota. I think I can take one or two questions.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I'm just waiting for just 10-15 students more.
Krish NAik: Yes, Rahul, you can go ahead.
Rahul Parihar: Paul, we.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rahul Parihar: Talking about the project.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Rahul Parihar: of AWS racks, so would… would it make sense to…
Rahul Parihar: have a project, for example, we all work as a solution architect, but the major gap is, there are ARB decks, and there are ARB reports, and there are known issues, you know, from people experience that we are documenting.
Rahul Parihar: So I wanted… I'm trying to, you know, do a… kind of a proof-of-concept of AWS native rack project with…
Rahul Parihar: Which, you know, helps to scan the, have it more recursive.
Rahul Parihar: you know, RAG implementation, where you, know it from your previous, historical, reference, solution reference board.
Krish NAik: Alright, Rausi, I got your, point. Okay, now I want to do a little bit different. See, I think in the last meeting, I asked Motaza, and I think Abhishek was also there. Ask me there. I think it will be better.
Krish NAik: Because there I can do a longer discussion here.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it. Okay, so probably, like, Monday, Tuesday, any day you can schedule a meeting, and I think then…
Krish NAik: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: I think it will be better for that particular project, that's why I asked some of those. I think last meeting you didn't join, but I told Abhishek, you guys can let me know at least one day, I can get an availability and connect with you, okay?
Rahul Parihar: And today's multimodel, RAG model, how it will be different than the one which we did it for text-to-SQL? Is it on the same line?
Krish NAik: Not in the same, see. First of all, like, I will be doing the local setup. It means the model, it, the weights are totally open, okay? So, and it has also the Volama support. The idea is that I'll be running the OCR model
Krish NAik: locally, the detection layout model on CPU, both the things. And later on, I will switch to GPU, because I know a lot of people might not have at least 32GB of RAM, because I feel in my 32GB, it's a little bit laggy, but again, somehow in CPU, I have done it.
Krish NAik: But, later on, once we do the inferencing on GPUs, you will understand it faster, because here, when I upload an entire PDF, let's take, like, 9 pages. That 9 pages might take 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: Because what happens, when you upload the image, so from that image, image will be extracted, tables will be extracted, formulas will be extracted. Okay, now once those extractions are done, like in the last class of multimodal we have discussed, I have used GPT-4. I'll be sending those, like, BBBox coordinates,
Krish NAik: To the, gPT-Puru, and it will be writing the caption.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in a particular chunk, so I'll be maintaining the modality. Like, this chunk is for image, this chunk is for table, this chunk is for formulas or equations.
Krish NAik: Based on that. So, most of the written types are available in the current OCR, like, I have picked up the GLM one, because in the last two to three weeks, a lot of OCRs
Krish NAik: came out, so Chandra OCR2, really a good one you guys can test out.
Krish NAik: I think in the last class also, I told, and the other one is from the Red Note team, they have also got their OCR. Okay, so two open source OCRs entirely the model, the weights are available in Hugging Face, so we will be utilizing one of them. Like, JLM, I felt that the response is quite good.
Krish NAik: Okay, how to manage the GPU? Okay, Rajat, I told you, for the last one, the notebook that I have shared for my learning, we need to execute it in Lightning AI, in collaborative.
Krish NAik: at least take an L4. Okay, having 24 GB of VRAM is required, because, see, multimodal, you need GPU. Without GPU, it is not possible only. I'll be showing you the inferencing on CPU, but you will really understand. We have to wait 5 minutes, 6 minutes, the processing time will be very, very high.
Krish NAik: And, I think last to last week, I told everybody, just get your Lightning accounts, at least you will be getting 15 credits. I think that is more than enough for today's
Krish NAik: And even for next week, you guys can utilize it. Okay, so the entirely, like, how to switch from local, so those things that we'll be talking about. So today's is pretty much, and I think next week we can continue with the discussion, or let's see, like, tomorrow if we can start.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think, most of you have joined.
Krish NAik: last question, I will be taking it from Rajat Amar. Just keep your question, I will take it later on, okay? Rajat, quickly go ahead and…
Krish NAik: ask a question, because I'm going to start the class soon.
Rajat Khanna: I'm audible.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so my question is, like, I was going through that, minor U code, so it, it looks like it's a fixed pattern code, like, while we are doing our,
Rajat Khanna: initial implementation, so it's a fixed pattern, so we will be doing, importing the, scenarios by regulating the CPU, GPU, and all. So, those are just fixed pattern, or is… we can change in those as well?
Krish NAik: You can change, because I have kept a certain piece of code for GPU detection, what is the GPU, what is the VRAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then only that will take place. So, you can do some changes, but always return… always understand that every model… because I told you in the last class, there are two important paradigms. Like, Mantage is asking what is the difference between Kolpali and Mineru.
Krish NAik: Kolpali, totally different. In Kolpali, you take a PDF, you'll be taking, converting that, each page of the PDF into an image, and directly embed it.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, and here, what we do. For the text, yes, we do maintain a chunk. For the image, a separate chunk, but what we do, the image, the table, we'll be sending it to a multimodal, like, GPT-40 for now, or you can use any multimodal, okay? And then we will be actually captioning it.
Krish NAik: Okay. I told you, like, two paradigms, Vantage, in the last class. One is take the entire image and convert it into an embedding.
Krish NAik: Really, it works, but the requirement is always a VRAN. You need always a GPU. But at least in this case, you can create lighter systems, where you have both the options, like the OCR part and the layout detection part. So for the layout detection, I told you, like, so many options are available, so you need to set up a combo.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, like, directly use some cloud APIs, like Text Track, Document Intelligence from Azure, those things are fine. But actually, if you're building a custom one, then you need to actually pick out the layout part, okay? And, with that layout detection, plus the visuals layout.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have, taken in this class the GLM OCR, I think in the last class we didn't discuss, but the main purpose is, with GLM OCR, the layout detection is actually integrated, so it becomes easier for me to show. It means that two different things. One, the OCR model, I'll be running it in my local.
Krish NAik: And then I will move to the, layout detection that I'll be running directly on my SQL, not in volume.
Rajat Khanna: And also, Paul, like, while we're using GPU, memory, and all those things, so do we need a driver as well?
Krish NAik: Why? Without Huda drivers, how we will do it?
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: guys, so I think, when the course will finish, I think, Moit, by the end of this month.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that a few small, small topics are there. I'm planning, we have enough time, so I know that those small, small topics which is out of this.
Krish NAik: servers, like, I was planning for contextual retrieval, then, vector-less RAG, patient edits… okay, a little bit from security perspective, prompt card.
Krish NAik: Okay, data poisoning, those type of topics I'll be discussing.
Rajat Khanna: And.
Krish NAik: Langra is there in your syllabus, I'm not talking about Langra. By default, the next project will be an agentic RAG thing that we'll be building.
Rajat Khanna: And MCP was also written in, in…
Krish NAik: Yeah, MCP chota, that's… I don't take it as, like, a big one, which will take a lot of time.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Token, actually, like, context pruning, that comes under token, like, token optimization.
Krish NAik: I'll be talking about context only. Okay, later.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine. So, I think, we are good to go to start. So, first of all, let me just open the GitHub and let me share, okay?
Krish NAik: You guys can take a peone.
Krish NAik: And for this project, we'll be doing the deployment in ECS.
Krish NAik: target.
Krish NAik: EFS, a lot of other AWS components that I'm playing, okay? So, just take this one.
Krish NAik: I think the deployment part next week, it will come soon.
Krish NAik: Today's strategies are local things who will be doing the setup.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody please take a clone.
Krish NAik: And then let me know.
Krish NAik: Moreover, can we also have a session on… yes, metadata enrichment also is there, don't worry, because I'll be showing you two different ways for metadata enrichment for every chunk. One is the Gleaner way. Okay, I really, right now, as I've been working, even I have taken Gleaner to production.
Krish NAik: So I feel that it's really good from the Fastino Labs, okay, as the open source model, I really feel a lot of open source people have joined, and I can say the contributions are really good. So… and the other one is through LangExtra, two separate ways.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody please take a clone and then let me know, because in my system, I think…
Krish NAik: Peso…
Krish NAik: Okay, so clone it, set up the environment.
Krish NAik: everything is there, so I think… Mohammad is asking, I know, we have a lot of ways and methods around. What are those methods, Mohammad, very specifically, that you were referring?
Krish NAik: Pretty much, I have shown you a lot of, stuff. So, what is the exact thing, Monmouth, your requirement? Tell me that one.
Krish NAik: Okay, I'll let you open that student.
Krish NAik: Can you please share the link? I think I have shared the link. Please let me know, the link is working. I think this is a public repo.
Krish NAik: Because before starting our application, a few things, that you guys need to, take care of. One is, like, just to be sure, I think I have the env.example. Okay, let me just see.
Krish NAik: Okay… What are the things?
Krish NAik: Okay, so this API key, leave it for now, a ZAI API key.
Krish NAik: Okay, just keep it none for now.
Krish NAik: Then, pass our backend, change it to Olama, as we'll be working with Olama, so… I think I can open my Ollama also.
Krish NAik: Biff, please. Holama is fine.
Krish NAik: And I think, Gina…
Krish NAik: Okay, quadrant, okay, quadrant needs to be started in your local host. Okay, so I think, that particular setup also you can do.
Krish NAik: For our re-ranker backend, okay.
Krish NAik: The GINA API key get it, okay. So I think it will be better, because if I try to run a Gwen model in local, then again.
Krish NAik: the idea is that at least let's focus on the core functionalities, the OCR and the other part. Because for your re-ranker also, I've used a VL module.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, vision-supported, re-ranker. So, that comes, so the GINA API, you can actually get it, and you can do the setup.
Krish NAik: Okay, so step by step, okay, a lot of setup are there. So, first of all, let me know the clone part and the environment creation part. These two things are done on me.
Krish NAik: And then we will move to the next file.
Krish NAik: Just example, we learned vector and grab what is the one used in the market? Hybrid moment.
Krish NAik: Boot.
Krish NAik: Because right now, everybody is moving that. You will be having your normal vectors, with that you will be having your graphs.
Krish NAik: So, like, a combination.
Krish NAik: And actually, like, when I say hybrid, it's pretty much a lot of hybrid words will come.
Krish NAik: Because, if I try to break hybrid this field according to multiple papers, okay, so let me just get it. So, when you actually see a hybrid.
Krish NAik: I don't know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the first meaning that comes is your… Spots.
Krish NAik: plus dense.
Krish NAik: Okay, then what are the other options that you can add? You can add multi-vector support, Colbert.
Krish NAik: After that, you can add graphs.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, generally, this is referred with respect to text.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, another hybrid which is used, in the field for hybrid, Normally.
Krish NAik: This is with respect to, images.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here what you would do?
Krish NAik: You take whole poly-based solutions, Okay?
Krish NAik: plus your… Layout.
Krish NAik: detection.
Krish NAik: Plus?
Krish NAik: Eurofiore.
Krish NAik: Now, this is another also combo. Now, think about if you actually try to mix it. Now, this is pretty much for…
Krish NAik: Multimodor.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so that hybrid, becomes much, you know. So that's why when I actually feel it becomes hybrid, hybrid, hybrid, okay. And actually, I've seen, like, people doing these type of solutions also, because I think in the,
Krish NAik: Next, what I'm planning for models routing much more, because actually, now, like, starting from the end of 2025, we use 3 models in production, so it's actually, like, through an agent, we take a decision that, okay, where it should be routed. One, a big model, like a GPT-5, then a smaller model.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then a much more smaller. So in that way, like, 3 different models. In that way, your solution becomes much better, I can say.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's much cheaper every time you don't need to hit the main APIs.
Krish NAik: Okay, so another multimodal solution, actually, like, framework that we do prefer.
Krish NAik: Which is using two different, engines. It means that in stage one, you will be using only pole. That is fine. The more you add, just remember the cost of your vector DB will increase much more. Okay, and in the second part, you'll be having, like, A,
Krish NAik: Okay, and I think, a B part.
Krish NAik: in A, I'll be using, let's take an ooze. Like, every OCR is not good in everything, so you have to understand, like, whenever you are doing RO testing, you have to actually pick up, okay? And probably here, I will go with, like, parallel VL.
Krish NAik: this combination also, like, like, using two separate OCRs. Okay, and with that. So in that way, like, you can be a full crew. Now, generally, the response time of these type of data ingestion pipelines with multimodal, it's high for one document, nothing we can do.
Krish NAik: Okay, you need a very, very good GPU if you want it, like, under 20 seconds or 30 seconds. Even today, if I go with an L4 having 24 GB VRAM, then also you will see that it will take close to, I think, 3 minutes at least.
Krish NAik: So, now, you can combine all these things. So, it totally depends upon you.
Krish NAik: Alright, please let me know cloning and environment part. Is it done?
Krish NAik: Then only I will move to the next part.
Krish NAik: Because you need to just, run with it, so I think already I have Ulama.
Krish NAik: I need a lot of terminals to take it.
Krish NAik: So, Ctrl-D, just check, pulllama hyphen hyphen…
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think Ulama is running, just do an Ulama list.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you will see that, like, in my case, I already have the GLM OCR latest, just be sure you have it in your system.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can do, like, an Ulama run and GLM OCR latest, so from this page, if you want, I'm sharing the link, you can download the model in your local…
Krish NAik: OpenClaw is good, but again, like, enterprise, really, like, I don't feel.
Krish NAik: Okay, because for enterprises, a lot of more customizations, that's why the latest update that came from OpenClow, I think 3.4, or that 3.7 update, after 1.4, a lot of security updates have been there, but I mean, yes.
Krish NAik: I feel that, for enterprises, at least for a few things, NemoClaw will be much better as compared to OpenClure. In OpenClaw, a lot of fixes that needs to be, taken into account.
Krish NAik: So, generally, like.
Krish NAik: I won't say you can do an entire setup, but really, not my preference now. Probably after 3 months, again, I will be doing the evaluation.
Krish NAik: Nemo Clow, I don't have, I think, Aglo or Chinese, but generally, I look into his content sometimes, and I feel that it's a really good dish.
Krish NAik: Because, for passing, I don't know how many of you know, I think last week, let pass came from Lama Index, and really, like, it can work in your local, so let pass…
Krish NAik: Gemini 3 voice agents came, so probably one session a little bit, because I think I was looking into that. So voice agents plus that one, Lit Pass part, both the things that also I'm planning as an extra class.
Krish NAik: So… I don't have any Python script, you can directly do the installation of it.
Krish NAik: to our docs.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please let me know the Ulama part is downloaded, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Okay, so… then comes… Now, Jinnah… ginah.ai.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, why I'm using Jenna? For my re-ranking. Okay, because this is a re-ranking DL model. Other models are there, so…
Krish NAik: Hugging paste.co.
Krish NAik: If quandary Ranker is there, that also we can use it. Then… I don't think…
Krish NAik: This one is really great SLM. Okay, through knowledge distillation that they have built. I don't know how many of you have done knowledge distillation? Anybody?
Krish NAik: Knowledge distillation, like, from a teacher, how to create a student, like, from an 8 billion one, how to make a 4 billion model, anybody has done those type of tasks?
Krish NAik: Because this is a really, really good model.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, as I was talking about, it was Gwen, actually, when Reid Anka
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, you have two options, the twin 3VL, okay, so let me increase the font a little bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 23VL, this one also you can use, or this one? But these will be local, you have to understand, you need a lot of RAM.
Krish NAik: If you don't
Krish NAik: then that's why I told you the alternate. At least in JINA, they have the API, so for our free, I can say for our initial tutorial, most of the things will be done. So you need to actually do a sign-up.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do assignment, because they have the de-ranker here, as you can see.
Krish NAik: to GINAR read anchor V3.
Krish NAik: Nat, we'll be using it.
Krish NAik: So, I felt that, and you can get the API key from
Krish NAik: So you don't need to pay anything, so initially there have been limits. And the idea is that, to the re-ranker, I won't be passing a lot of chunks. Okay, let's pass only,
Krish NAik: like, the final output, I can say, let's get only 5 chunks. So, the idea is, let's pass 10 from there, retrieval, and then. So, don't try to pass a lot of chunks.
Krish NAik: then I feel that your limit will be quickly exhausted, okay? So, jinnah.ai, just try to sign up and get an API key.
Krish NAik: Buodge… Re-ranker, I don't feel. You can't use that.
Krish NAik: You can use it, but you have to understand the performance of the rear ankles will be much less.
Krish NAik: You should have multimodal support. V rank 25, multilingual, optimized again.
Krish NAik: No. Not this.
Krish NAik: You need with VL support, vision support, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why I have moved ahead with Gene.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can risk when also. Otherwise, manually, you can write and you can ask. I have kept all those options in the code.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, later on, but initially, take the GINAP, okay? It will be easy for you.
Krish NAik: For re-anchor, we can use Colbert.
Krish NAik: No?
Krish NAik: See, Mantaj, I'm talking about VL support, if there is VL support.
Krish NAik: Colbert is pretty much text-based. Kolipal is image-based.
Krish NAik: Those are image encoders which are being used.
Krish NAik: Generally for, Raid anchors, we need cross encoders with, vision support.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I won't say a lot of models are available, but yes, few models out there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think, like, the free one,
Krish NAik: later on, because, see, for the CPU purpose, as you can see here, with the VL support.
Krish NAik: This is one, but again, you need a good amount of RAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, for this one. Because, creating an entire quench stack, I will say that it's good, and the 2 billion model does the job in our case.
Krish NAik: But again, like, running it in your loo… how many things you will run in your local? Ulama you will run, document detection you will run. I don't think you guys have… if you have GPUs, really good.
Krish NAik: Preferable, but for now, that's why use Jinna. I say that it's much easier, okay? You can get as a simple API key. They have an API key option.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can see, I think close to, like, 10 million tokens they have, I think, yes. For our task, 10 million is…
Krish NAik: More than fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please get it.
Krish NAik: And then let me know.
Krish NAik: Because in my environment, majorly, I feel that, when I go here.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you can use text embedding 3 large, I have used switch to text embedding, 3 small for OpenAI.
Krish NAik: If so…
Krish NAik: Gemini support is also there, you can test it, but really, I have not done the testing of that one.
Krish NAik: Okay, Gemini. Quadrant URL, fine.
Krish NAik: At least, I think for this one… because, see, I have taken multiple backends for re-ranker, but initially just take Jenna. I feel that Jinna will be better.
Krish NAik: Because for OpenAI, you will be making an API call. It's just like through an prompt, you will ask.
Krish NAik: So, step by step. So, now, you told earlier the voice editing anger is great, Mitesh, for text.
Krish NAik: Okay, API key is done, ULAMA, GLM installed, ZAPI key? No, no, no, no, no. ZAPI key, it's not free. You have to pay, so leave that part Rahu, because we'll be running our, GLM OCR model in local.
Krish NAik: They have been hosted inferals, I can say that's much faster, but leave it. I don't feel we need that. Question, feel free to answer.
Krish NAik: Generating rules for product configuration. Generating rules.
Krish NAik: instruction-based things that can be done, but again, if you have a question of integration for a product integration, product space.
Krish NAik: Hello.
Krish NAik: Yes, we can do that moment, okay? But, later on, we'll be talking.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, just be sure you are setting up… I think I have already given the commands in testing.md, there will be one markdown file. Okay, so… I think somewhere this test, test, test, yes. Open this file, okay, and I think majorly all the commands are there, for this class that you need.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… leave the ZAI, okay, just pass your OpenAI API key.
Krish NAik: Okay, so through OpenAI API key, like, captioning I'm doing, I'm doing embeddings, you can even re-ranking.
Krish NAik: is possible, but I feel that Gina Rina Ankar is much better than that.
Krish NAik: So this is one. Then the re-ranker backend, paste your API key, JINA API key, and the re-ranker backend as JIN. Okay, so please do these configurations.
Krish NAik: Which script has OpenAI settings? Does I have to add the base URL for… I think.
Krish NAik: Why you need to add the base UR?
Krish NAik: Okay, is it, from a different, service provider than your main one?
Krish NAik: Okay, Azure Content.
Krish NAik: Well…
Krish NAik: In the first part, I don't think you're… right now, you need an OpenAI API key, because we will start with the passing part, and the passing part, you really don't need. But, later on, inside your, if you go into the scripts folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, inside the scripts folder, when you will see that you have the ingest.py, please do have a check on it.
Krish NAik: That is the main warning, yes.
Krish NAik: Alright, please let me know, because I feel that I can…
Krish NAik: Start my Docker. Okay, so Docker Compose app quadrant.
Krish NAik: Beautiful.
Krish NAik: Let me just, start my quadrant also in the meeting.
Krish NAik: Okay, it looks like I'm not switched on Docker, just… start your Docker team and also green.
Krish NAik: I thought my Docker Compose is configured for a quadrant directly, just…
Krish NAik: Baruch, I can do a Docker run also, that is fine, but
Krish NAik: How to get the Jinna API key? Go to jinnah.ai, sign up, and get the API key, Mantach.
Krish NAik: I think, you have your PyProject.2ml file, you can do an invasion.
Krish NAik: Open Docker, Docker. Okay… Right? Docker has not started it yet, so…
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me start the documents.
Krish NAik: No, no, that API is a different one, no. Below that, in your ENV, I think I've already shared the…
Krish NAik: env.example.
Krish NAik: Please go through that file.
Krish NAik: Here you have your JINA API here, separate environment variable.
Krish NAik: What happened to my Docker? Why it's not starting?
Krish NAik: There is some issue with my docker.
Krish NAik: Relief.
Krish NAik: All right, looks like the container is up. Okay, so just be sure you have that, and I can do a local host to this one. So, okay, I'm getting the response. It means that my, quadrant is pretty much working. And for your manual EY verification, you can open your, local host.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is actually not increasing.
Krish NAik: You can open localhost, And go for 6333. That is the dashboard that you get it. 633 dashboard.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think I do have already that one, but I will delete.
Krish NAik: Okay, so make sure the quadrant is up.
Krish NAik: Right now, we don't need, but later on, we'll be switching on. So, just be sure the container is up and working. For ingestion, I need.
Krish NAik: Z underscore API key is not required.
Krish NAik: Openai API key is required, and Jenna is required.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, leave that part, leave that part. Okay, keep it as none for now in the API part, if you want to pass it. Just pass none, NOA any.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the setup is done.
Krish NAik: So, everybody, I think you guys can get the Jenna API key, yes or no?
Krish NAik: It's pretty much easy, just sign up and get the API key. It takes time, I think 1 or 2 minutes, but after that, your key will be pretty much activated.
Krish NAik: Z.ai, no, actually, see, we'll be using the EYPI, here, okay? Yes.
Krish NAik: Now, here, this is the actual package that we are using in this one, okay.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a really good one, I can say. Okay, so here, like, my detection model will be PP Dock Loud V3. I think this came around January 26, 29, that was the time, the last class I already showed you. This is based on Paddle.
Krish NAik: Ocr, open source, layout, model. Okay, now this is the one. So, we already have it in Hugging Face.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, there is a layout detection one, so, like, we'll… we have already… I've kept all these things in PyProject.2ml, so directly you can do the installation of these packages. So, the SDK is available, so directly you can use it.
Krish NAik: Now comes, like, you can get the API key from here. So, like, big open, sorry, I don't use this one.
Krish NAik: I think… said… dot EI.
Krish NAik: Let's so… When I go to the API section.
Krish NAik: So, within API trees… okay, from here, actually, you have to create the APIs. But,
Krish NAik: Though I have a coding plan, from Z.ai, but actually didn't came, so I have to do the recharge. Okay, then again, I added some credits just for initial testing that the response is coming good or bad.
Krish NAik: Okay, for that part.
Krish NAik: But I feel that you guys don't need, because the weights are totally open, so that's why Olama support is already there, as mentioned. So if you go below.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see that, VLLM support is also there, so actually for production, it's good. So, you can see option 3 OLAMA. So, this is the Ollama deployment part, if you're actually… so I have shifted to this particular way.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I feel that it's easier, so in that way, you don't need actually an API.
Krish NAik: So that, you should understand, yes, for, scanned handwritten documents, again, I feel that GLM OCR is not good in that. In that case, you have to change the OCR engine to, like, parallel VL, okay, if you ask, if you want to really check this one.
Krish NAik: Pardon OCRVL, okay?
Krish NAik: I think this, that came, yes. The OCR 1.5. This is really good in that one. Can handwritten. JLM OCR is much better, I feel, for digital PDFs. So that's why I told you, you know, the hybrid engine, we first of all detect
Krish NAik: Like, what type of document, a digital one or a handwritten one, kind of one? Okay, and then we move ahead moment. In that way, you can create open source solutions.
Krish NAik: Okay, please do check out, like, if you're really interested in the OCRs, the new two OCRs, the Chandra OCR2 and the Red Note one. They… actually, in their paper, they are mentioned about, like, multimodal OCR, they use it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I've done the testing, like, all are now equal, pretty much saturated results, there's not, like, very far away.
Krish NAik: But, yes.
Krish NAik: This is finally how it looks like, but Minoru, really awesome, because I feel minor root does the job most of the times.
Krish NAik: But again, very heavy, very problematic thing to run in your own machine.
Krish NAik: You need always requests. Okay, so everybody, please let me know, quadrant top, JINA API key, OpenAI API key.
Krish NAik: Olama, everything, the setup is done or not.
Krish NAik: Till Quadrant is done, fine. If Till Quadrant is done, at least let's start moving into the OCR, because I feel that you guys have not explored the OCR, so first of all, let's explore it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, let's switch here, okay?
Krish NAik: I think I can just clear it up.
Krish NAik: Now, what I can do… so, first of all, create a folder and create, and just keep on PDF for now. Okay, in my case, I don't think I have shared this, but, create a folder like test data. Okay, so here I've kept the docklink report.
Krish NAik: So at least keep one report, don't keep a very long PDF, because the response time is already high, 5 to 6 minutes it will take on the CP. Okay, so keep something small, or just be sure that you are taking something small. I don't want a very long PDF. And at least, how many of you are having
Krish NAik: 32GB of RA, even tell me in the chat.
Krish NAik: And how many of you are on 16?
Krish NAik: If you have something more than 32, really, you don't need to write, but
Krish NAik: People, 24GB, 24GB will do the job.
Krish NAik: 16 GB dialti, Motada, okay.
Krish NAik: Really, like, because ULAMA will only take… because in my 32GB, it becomes laggy.
Krish NAik: Yes, I get a lot of… so just keep one. In that case, just take one page or two pages.
Krish NAik: Okay, and which page? Let's do that, okay? I've… I'm telling you exactly what to do, because my main,
Krish NAik: Idea is that, let me just open, I love PDF.com.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think, let me merge PDF, I don't want to merge split, I think split option. Let me take a file, and if you want, just reduce the number of pages.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is from range, let's go this way into…
Krish NAik: Ages, okay? So I know exactly, because where there is text, I'm not really worried about.
Krish NAik: But, at least, 3 things that I can do.
Krish NAik: For the replacement.
Krish NAik: I'm actually focusing on only the images and the tables, so a smaller version that I will be doing the testing. In that way, if you want, you can do a quick crop and keep it.
Krish NAik: Oops.
Krish NAik: Think.
Krish NAik: They have obtained some of them.
Krish NAik: All right. So, similarly, just do it according to your one, okay, sister. So, I will start with the, first things. Okay, so first of all, I will, go to the visualizer part, and I will show you a few things. So, like, let me check here.
Krish NAik: Removing the folder, I think.
Krish NAik: Oh, Lama. I do have few things here, so I don't feel it is actually required. Let me delete everything from the output.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can actually open the script of test underscore pass. API, don't use the script, that one.
Krish NAik: I think, you couldn't care.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the first script that I'll be executing is test underscore parse, okay? Now, this is for your local OLAMA. API underscore parse is actually if you're having the z dot API key, but I think we are not working with that, so leave that. Now, this is a simple parsing script, okay, where I'll be passing the PDF and I'll be saving the output.
Krish NAik: In a folder, okay? So what you can do, you can just copy one of the commands, I think, like, the last one from here.
Krish NAik: Okay? And, go to your terminal, let's paste it, and just be sure you are updating the path to the PDF.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, I think,
Krish NAik: My folder name is a little bit different.
Krish NAik: Test underscore data, so whichever folder you have created, test underscore data slash
Krish NAik: I think documentreport.pdf that I can do.
Krish NAik: Okay? See? Just copy-paste the command.
Krish NAik: If you, execute the first one, because, yes, image can also be passed, or, image and PDF,
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm just passing a PDF for now. Then I'm telling what is my input.
Krish NAik: And where, actually, I want to save the output. In the output, it will be a JSON file, basically. Okay, that is basically how the output of the model looks like. There will be having the bounding boxes, everything.
Krish NAik: So, I will start the execution in the meantime, if you guys want, because this will take 5 to 6 minutes.
Krish NAik: Yes, so…
Krish NAik: And suddenly, the RAM usage in my system will be very high. I will be closing the videos, okay?
Krish NAik: So, actually, you can see, this is a GLM OCR initialized in self-hosted mode, and just tell me, like, the audio might also lag, because the system usage in my
Krish NAik: Because of ulama will be very, very high. Can you share the command? It's in the script.
Krish NAik: Mantage?
Krish NAik: download the doc filling technical report from web browser. In the last class, we have used so many times that PDF.
Krish NAik: It's the Dockling Technical Report.
Krish NAik: Just check, no module name for Torch, then just install Torch.
Krish NAik: Okay, and please do GLM OCRC, like, if you are missing this one, I'm just telling you, Rahul, check this one, so I think I have taken that testing.md, open that file.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in this testing.md, actually, I've kept it. For your development, you do this pip install hyphen e.tel. So I know that under, project.2ml, project, project, project, okay, so I do have, majorly…
Krish NAik: The ones with respect to BG… okay, you can install the layout part also. I think if this is missing, it won't work.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can add dot layout in that way, and you can do the installation. You can do pip install GLMOCR within the brackets layout, that also works. In whichever way, just be sure Torch is available.
Krish NAik: Because here, I haven't kept the layout part for the layout detection inside my main dependencies.
Krish NAik: Because that's an optional one, so you can even look here into the… so I'm just telling all the options.
Krish NAik: Because the layout model needs to be there, okay? So here…
Krish NAik: Right now, the self-hosted one, which is basically, through this one, layout detection can also be installed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so multiple ways, whichever way that you feel that you can meet the SDK workout.
Krish NAik: Got it, working now? Alright, Monmouth, UV Sync? Yes, UV Sync, you can do it.
Krish NAik: But, for now, I will suggest do the normal one and do the layout one. Only two things are in.
Krish NAik: Because, a lot of testing things are there, rough, linting, those things. Right now, it's not required.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see, like, the… till now, the GLM OCR, initialized mode. Okay.
Krish NAik: I think the output will be saved.
Krish NAik: This will really… 5 minutes, 6 minutes, let's taken my system. On GPUs, it takes 3 minutes, at least on an L4, that I have done the testing.
Krish NAik: Mine is completed travel, great. Then, in your case, your system, I think.
Krish NAik: is better than mine. I have an M1 Pro with 32GB.
Krish NAik: So, can you show your, ULAMA quadrant is coming as the folder name? Can you show your ulama, my ulama?
Krish NAik: Ulama, what do you want to know in Ulama?
Krish NAik: Because I have just, like, Ulama, what do you want me to do? Ulama list?
Krish NAik: Or, what one? The folder structure are you talking about?
Krish NAik: This is under Ulama, the output will come.
Krish NAik: This is actually… Okay, so under this output folder.
Krish NAik: Ula ma termino.
Krish NAik: I'm not open to anything ulama in the town.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, see, everybody who don't have a PDF, get a PDF. Just, right here, a doc link, technical, report, done.
Krish NAik: This is the only thing that you have to do.
Krish NAik: Open the PDF, download it.
Krish NAik: In the last class, we have used it so many times.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can see that, you can see, right here, majorly, like, the output is there, and, it took time.
Krish NAik: let's take 4 minutes or 5 minutes, but, it's done. So, you will see that here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just close this, files, all files, testing. So, two files are here. One is the,
Krish NAik: report element.json. So, using this file, actually, I can do the visualization. Okay, and then I have the docklink report, so this is exactly
Krish NAik: That one. Now, I think for the authors, they have created a table. Fine, but, really, it's not required, I can say.
Krish NAik: Then, okay, I can see image if it is there, it has been taken through a bounding box coordinates, BBox is there, fine. I can actually send it for captioning. Rest of the outputs just have an analysis on.
Krish NAik: Okay, and really, like, I know that most of you won't be comfortable so much with,
Krish NAik: I can say text. Okay, what you can do, actually, let's,
Krish NAik: to start the visualization part, because this part is done. What I will do now, give me run ScreamLit.
Krish NAik: Okay? And there is a visualize.py file. UV run, streamlit run, olama slash visualize. I'll just open this one. So, using this one, I have the JSON file, so I will pass the JSON file to do the rendering of the element, so that you guys can really understand that how those things work, okay?
Krish NAik: So, visualize.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is how the UI looks like.
Krish NAik: Pullama document. Okay, so first of all, I need the original PDF for rendering. Okay, I will just pass the PDF. Doclink report is there, and I think I can actually do the loading.
Krish NAik: Okay, Shoot, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: Actually, not the parsing part, sorry. Yes. Okay, don't do the parsing here, for now, leave this part. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Now, can you guys see the main, objective? Like, this is actually the output. So, so I think you guys can change the page also. It will work, pretty much.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think this is an image, so… Based on the rendered results… Okay, text, paragraph title.
Krish NAik: Okay, table, you can see this is the main table.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, now this is completely one inference block. Then comes the next one, again, an image that it has taken. It's fine, not an issue, but, do the visualization.
Krish NAik: Even if I have a 32 still stuck on, layout pipe install, all right, Mitesh, it takes time, see, initially, like, for me, also, the setup takes time, but I've just shown you the output of the OCR right now, and really, the output of the OCR is great, I can say. There won't be any type of problems.
Krish NAik: Just you have to execute millin, test, parse that particular file.
Krish NAik: Once you have done your test pass, you will see that the output will be coming. Once the output is done, this output, I'll be rendering it through Streamly 2. So that, rather than looking into the text, you guys can look into the bounding boxes exactly.
Krish NAik: Okay, Motaza, you can have a try on that one, the trimmed version.
Krish NAik: The way that I have done, you guys have to do the same thing. First of all, test parse. Once the parsing is done, then run Olama Visualize.
Krish NAik: Can you send the stimulate command?
Krish NAik: That's UV Run, Streamlit.
Krish NAik: I think it will be there, and just wait. Let me see, like, whether it's there somewhere. Because in the READEME file or somewhere, I might have added that.
Krish NAik: Streamlit, have I added, Streamlit part?
Krish NAik: No, this is the REST API, haven't added that.
Krish NAik: The command is simple… okay, yes, you can, see. This one is there.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, this one. So, UV run…
Krish NAik: then streamlit, run, ulama is the folder, slash visualize is the script that we are executing.
Krish NAik: If you want, you can take it from here, otherwise I'm pasting it again in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because the first step is looking into the output of the OCRs, and I felt that the layout detection is working fine, if the layout detection is really working, so I have nothing to worry about.
Krish NAik: Okay, if the, somehow, the results of the detection fails, because if you remember in the last week, we tested LimotonPass. In remote-out pass, it's a unified model. In a single model, you have the layout detection support, as well as the
Krish NAik: OCR support, but it failed in the last few phases. Initially, it worked great, but in the last few pages. But here, I can say that it's pretty much working fine, so no issues.
Krish NAik: So, please do the testing, see, it will take time. So, for a few, it can be faster, for a few, it can be a little bit, there. And, just be sure you are not doing the parsing here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, the parsing is not required. I think automatically the JSON file should be fetched, okay, and after that, below a PDF upload option will come. Just select that. Really, you don't need to do any parsing.
Krish NAik: So I've taken the elements also, what are the different elements, like charts, table, figures. This is the return type from the OCM.
Krish NAik: Okay? And, the images here, this particular image, actually, like, through our rack, my idea will be, let's ask questions from this image much more. Because text thinks, easily it can be hardened. Or I have to ask some questions from this particular table.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly, I will try to perform that during my retrieval, this is the actual thing, my main focus around. The image and the table format.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, when you are doing, actually, I think people, who have selected that one, in the Z API part, just wait, let me just…
Krish NAik: Just to wait, because I think I do have my ZPL key here. I'll be showing my ENP file, just keep it lightened.
Krish NAik: Take it? Yes.
Krish NAik: Just be sure in red underscore AI API key you have passed none.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in the parser backend, it's Solana. Everybody, please do have a check on this one.
Krish NAik: Next, buddy.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please check this one.
Krish NAik: if it's written near cloud, so the cloud API will be triggered.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure it's kept as none for now. So, automatically, it will switch to alone.
Krish NAik: Abhishey was telling you, JLM OCR layout is missing.
Krish NAik: Not, just food.
Krish NAik: in my piperoject.2ML, where it's a 2M query.
Krish NAik: Yet, there are no.
Krish NAik: Lita, butche.
Krish NAik: That is under that one notion.
Krish NAik: Okay, Milan, I see this, pipeline started. Okay, yes.
Krish NAik: Everybody will see this log, see. Whenever you are starting, you will see this one.
Krish NAik: GLA Musiyar via Ulama, okay? I think. And after that, you will see something like this, and then it will start.
Krish NAik: It will take time, 4-5 minutes, but, just wait.
Krish NAik: Rajat, that is fine, that is a warning. Leave that. If you are getting any deprecated warnings, that won't hamper anything.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that this practice is better for Linux-based systems or for Windows, I don't know, like, it is possible, but really, you need to handle the dependencies. And most of the dependencies are actually much more supportable from Linux point and Mac
Krish NAik: So just habit check, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Till the visualization part, everybody reached or not.
Krish NAik: Because it's simple, easy, first you do the parsing, you get the JSON file. Once you have the JSON file, you can actually render it on top of the original UI.
Krish NAik: How many of you got the result? Please let me know, for how many of you, because at least I feel a few might have good gigs. Where I will see the JSON, where you will be passing this output.
Krish NAik: Hyphen, hyphen output.
Krish NAik: Okay, million.
Krish NAik: Where you have passed the folder, just like me, I've kept it like ollama slash output.
Krish NAik: If you have used that one, simply inside that, you'll be having the JSON file.
Krish NAik: You'll be having the JSON file and the Markdown file, both the files.
Krish NAik: The structure will be something like this.
Krish NAik: Similarly, like, if I pick up some other file, okay, And,
Krish NAik: I really, like, just wait.
Krish NAik: Downloads this one.
Krish NAik: Best did.
Krish NAik: test… let me just add one variable name, okay?
Krish NAik: And, let me see… It was the test paths file.
Krish NAik: I've taken a smaller version of the PDF right now, but I think it should work for everyone.
Krish NAik: Please let me know for how many of you it is working.
Krish NAik: We're not just telling parser failed. PP doc will…
Krish NAik: That is fine, actually. This is a deprecated issue, actually. Like, that is not an error. Okay, parsing failed. It means that RAM…
Krish NAik: See, OLAMA will automatically shut down. If there is shortage of RAM, it will only say, like, a memory issue or something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Viraj, everyone, see, yes, saved, then great. Wherever you are actually saving it, you need that particular millenn, so I can see that, yes.
Krish NAik: Stopping the pipeline? Yes, so, yes, it worked in your case, Melind.
Krish NAik: Abhishek, okay, try pip install. Yes, you have to do the installation for the layout part, GLM OCR within the brackets layout. Directly try to do that, and add UB before that, because I think if you are working with UV, you need to do that.
Krish NAik: UVPIP install, then the layout part.
Krish NAik: Tell me, because this is…
Krish NAik: I know, like, multimodal setups are a little bit tough, but you people can let me…
Krish NAik: Like, anybody who is feeling that, I'm totally lost.
Krish NAik: Because things will be… once I start moving into GPUs.
Krish NAik: Because everything, I've kept it in Dockerfile, so it will be easier there.
Krish NAik: But at least, Rishab is telling it's taking time. For sure, it will take time, I know. For me, also, it took 4 to 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: In the next step, visualize, yes. For the visualize part.
Krish NAik: You have to just run uv run, streamlit run, and inside the olama folder, you have a visualage.piFi.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that visualize.py file is there, so you have to just execute that.
Krish NAik: API Server Return Status API. Till now, I've not started anything with respect to APIs.
Krish NAik: So, Mantach, I will be looking into your error. The next step is visualize. Yes, once the test parse script has successfully executed, what you will do, you'll be running the visualize part. Once you do the visualization.
Krish NAik: you will see that this will come. When this is there, what you need to do?
Krish NAik: Fine, I… okay, I think first I need a random PDF from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, two times…
Krish NAik: Okay, before I load… actually, you don't need to do anything parse with OLAMA, rather than just pass your original.
Krish NAik: you will see that, based on the results, you'll be getting it. So, parsing is really not required.
Krish NAik: I'll be just loading the JSON results directly.
Krish NAik: Dinesh is asking, you are converting the PDF to Markdown to store it into VectorTV? No.
Krish NAik: The idea is that if I have a Markdown file, it's better structured. Actually, later on, I can use it for, chunking and other things also. And the return type of the OCR, that from there, I can actually have an HTML-based output or markdown. That is the output of the OCR finish. Later on, if I have much more structure, actually, I can…
Krish NAik: to apply better chunking. So that's why an intermediary, form of 5.
Krish NAik: Because in VectorDB, at the end of the day, we save embedding smoothly.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Mantaj, while executing, UV run python olama slash testparse, test data docklink.pdf output olama, getting, status code 404, memory issues.
Krish NAik: Memory issues, memory issues, that's it.
Krish NAik: See, like, how much RAM you have, Mantash. That is the main thing. People who might get an error RAM already have told you. If you have lesser RAM, you can do it. 16GB. Windows or Mac.
Krish NAik: Mac, because I think 16GB Mac
Krish NAik: Motada told it worked for him. Take a smaller PDF, one page or two-page, and test it out.
Krish NAik: Arun is telling you, we run Python, okay, fine, getting, this as output.
Krish NAik: No, go on… What is the output, Aruna? I could not understand only.
Krish NAik: Okay, M18GB, taken 3 pages. Alright, 3 pages fine. Per initials testing, because once you have these majorly, we use GPUs, but I feel that it's fine. We can proceed ahead next for the, API testing part.
Krish NAik: one Chinese character, you got a new output file. Yes, JLM is from…
Krish NAik: China, so… one Chinese character you got, I'm really not sure about.
Krish NAik: And that one.
Krish NAik: Below is an upload option, no, upload the PDF, and you will be getting…
Krish NAik: receive status 500 from OCR API.
Krish NAik: Why the OCR API is being hit? I don't think you will be hitting, because you are using OLAMA. Rajat, check in your file, in the Z API key. Are you passing none, or…
Krish NAik: That… that part checked.
Krish NAik: Got this doc parser processing one output,
Krish NAik: This is fine, that is a deprecated… see, people don't tell me deprecated warnings.
Krish NAik: Okay, Methje, it's a deprecated thing, I'm…
Krish NAik: Because after that, if it automatically stops, it means that memory is there. Because Ullama will automatically kill that process. That's how Ulama works, nothing that I can do from my scene.
Krish NAik: Alright, Modaza, you were asking how we'll approach the embeddings. See, simply, text will be handled. Now, what I will do, for your anything,
Krish NAik: Because, see, normally text can be handled directly, my… any journey. All I'm worried about, about my formulas, my tables, my images. Now, those things, what I will do, I will actually send it to the GPT photo, I'll be creating captions.
Krish NAik: Okay, once the captions are there, I'll be creating structured captions, not simply one-liner captions. So from there, then I will do the jump.
Krish NAik: Okay, don't worry. During the ingestion pipeline, I'll be showing that.
Krish NAik: If you have kept it, I think this is fine. Z underscore API dot, then it should not actually hit the API.
Krish NAik: It should be your local one indeed.
Krish NAik: Yes, at the end of the day, it will be everything in the, text form.
Krish NAik: And, with every chunk, I'll be maintaining the modality, that this chunk is of an image, this chunk is of a table, this chunk is of a text, and that removal.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a little bit of… we call it layout-aware chunking, or structure-aware chunking for that particular approach we have created.
Krish NAik: 2 out of 3 is done, it's 500,
Krish NAik: 2 out of 3, if it is done, it means that you are hitting the API.
Krish NAik: I feel you are hitting the API.
Krish NAik: because you guys don't have the APID, then…
Krish NAik: I think some free limits that you can actually hit it, but… because, see, whenever you are running your test script, just be sure this is the option you are getting, let's see. This one. GLM OCR via OLAMA.
Krish NAik: It means that if I pass another PDF, let me just close this one, okay? I'm again running another, the smaller version of that one.
Krish NAik: What was that? Just wait. UV? RAN, I'm passing another one for now. So, first of all, I need to,
Krish NAik: Python?
Krish NAik: Olama, okay? Now, this PDF, I have a smaller PDF this time.
Krish NAik: making dockly. This one is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this time, that smaller version, 3 to 5 pages.
Krish NAik: And the rest of the things looks good.
Krish NAik: You will see this one, GLM via Ulama.
Krish NAik: Whoever is running.
Krish NAik: It should not be via cloud.
Krish NAik: Or via Z API, something like that.
Krish NAik: You will see that GLM OCR initialized in self-hosted mode.
Krish NAik: If it is Olama, then I think fine, I think…
Krish NAik: Please check this one, GLM OCR initialized in self-hosted mode. This is a much one, because I think this, actually, I'm printing it. A print statement is here.
Krish NAik: No, right now, I won't be taking the sharing part later.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that you are hitting the API somehow.
Krish NAik: 500, you get generally from APIs, that's fine.
Krish NAik: After this line, it stopped, it means that a RAM issues. After this, if it stops, simply it means that memory issues are there.
Krish NAik: Nothing that you can do from your side.
Krish NAik: Start getting empty markdown output file, but elements in .json file contents.
Krish NAik: I don't think it can happen, Nagesh, but really, let me say, because I feel that,
Krish NAik: In the output, you'll be getting… I mean, MD format.
Krish NAik: So… Yes, you can run this in Lightning, I don't know.
Krish NAik: The same thing can be done.
Krish NAik: Generally, for my FastAPI app, I have kept it in Lightning AI.
Krish NAik: But I felt that this, locally, you guys can do it.
Krish NAik: Because it will take 4-5 minutes for me also, like, 3 pages also.
Krish NAik: Because two models are running on my CPU. One is the OCR model, one is the layout detection model.
Krish NAik: That's why later on I thought about I cannot run the re-ranker. You can see here, it's done. Okay, and now I have the output. So, if I go back to my VS code, if I look into the output, you can see this 325. This is the new one, this is the elements.json.
Krish NAik: It has pretty much… because in the first one, okay, some polygons, content.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much, I feel that, really. The result is good, this is the markdown file. Now, this result, if I want to do the rendering.
Krish NAik: Now, the next step is the rendering part. If you really want to do… start your, streamlet, okay, so load this 3 to 5, automatically it will be, and then, just select the PDF file for your rendering.
Krish NAik: Look at the smaller one that I've taken, you can see directly.
Krish NAik: full, document markdown, layout analysis, table structure recognization, so I can say that yes.
Krish NAik: I have a check on this one, because yes, you can do the visualization of this.
Krish NAik: Till this point you guys are done, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Are we extracting? No, nothing weird. We can actually do that, Viraj, because we have the mounting box coordinates. We can actually extract image. It means that if you want any type of cropping.
Krish NAik: If I have the bounding box information,
Krish NAik: So, really, in that case, not required.
Krish NAik: Again, you don't need to save each image.
Krish NAik: If you have the bounding box coordinates, those coordinates also you can pass it.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is asking, can't parse on Windows. Alright, fine, because I know this…
Krish NAik: Might not be working for everyone.
Krish NAik: JLM output is good, I will say it's a good amount, because other OCRs are there, but everybody is not an OLAMA support. Otherwise, I will be switching to Red Note, the OCR that came from the Red Note team, it's a really good one.
Krish NAik: But, Ullama support is not good. It becomes much harder.
Krish NAik: You can do the executions, everything in Lightning AI. But, just till this point, everybody, please tell me that we have done it.
Krish NAik: Seeing some type of output.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, people, for whom the API is invoked.
Krish NAik: Like, the first version that comes, like, invoking the APIs.
Krish NAik: Just tweet.
Krish NAik: Because how the API will be invoked, that only I am telling.
Krish NAik: pinging.
Krish NAik: Because if you, check my… if I go to the Ulama folder.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I have test underscore parse.
Krish NAik: Here, everything is olama. So, how it's getting invoked, that I'm thinking.
Krish NAik: And just be sure you are not executing API underscore pass.py.
Krish NAik: If you're working with that, then that will hit, actually. But this one is purely based on…
Krish NAik: Olama. So, I think the output should come, and it should not hit the API, because for others, it's working, so I feel that for you also it should work.
Krish NAik: Because this is a print statement, so don't focus on this one.
Krish NAik: Once the initialization of the parser is done, then you get that self-hosted mode.
Krish NAik: That is the main one.
Krish NAik: Through which you can do it.
Krish NAik: Because here, I have not mentioned anything, like, hit the API or something yet.
Krish NAik: And even in the API part.
Krish NAik: If you are passing it none, then really it should not hit.
Krish NAik: Okay, please let me know, can we proceed to the next part of the practical?
Krish NAik: This is only related to the Olama folder.
Krish NAik: This config file, this is actually for your Ullama GLM setup.
Krish NAik: This config file is actually… because, when you actually go, and if you check here.
Krish NAik: the one, because still I'm not talking about the codebase, but as you ask the question, I'm telling you. So here, once you go with your, Ullama support here, ULAMA deployment.
Krish NAik: Volama deploy folder, let me just open it.
Krish NAik: So, here you will be having that config file. Can you see this config.yml? A certain structure is maintained here.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that. Whoever was asking, I think Milith could move.
Krish NAik: Yes, by default, yes, it is, you don't need to do anything more, those are correct.
Krish NAik: code base, I think, next week, but at least for today, just be sure it's up and working. Because then I want to move to the next phase. Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Can we proceed ahead, or should I wait 2 to 3 minutes, and then…
Krish NAik: Let me know, let me know, guys, in the chat.
Krish NAik: Summit is telling we can proceed. What about others, at least?
Krish NAik: More people use, or you guys are till now doing it in your local place. Update it.
Krish NAik: This is actually from, the actual SDK of GLM OCR. There, we are passing, like, how many output tokens that you need from the OCR code and other things.
Krish NAik: at all.
Krish NAik: I am nothing because of… Okay, don't think about, we will switch to lightning, don't worry. Because, for me, I know that. For a few of you, it might not work, but don't worry.
Krish NAik: At least he not here, then there we will do it.
Krish NAik: Yes, today, it's the output of the layout detection model and the OCR.
Krish NAik: Till now, only we have done two things. Because the first step of a multimodal rag is to explore the paradigm A and the paradigm B.
Krish NAik: In the last, week, we have already discussed, so we are right now the paradigm B.
Krish NAik: That's telling llama.cpp. Right now, we are not talking about quantization, Rajat.
Krish NAik: You could pass to GPT, then GPT will
Krish NAik: Because, generally it will crash, that's why.
Krish NAik: And if it crashes, nothing that we can do.
Krish NAik: Alright, the next part.
Krish NAik: So, let's start with the next part. So, majorly, the entire source code is inside this doc parser folder inside SRC. You have your, like, all the APIs, I think 3 or 4 APIs that I have.
Krish NAik: One is the ingest, the document ingestion pipeline, and the second one is the retrieval, and the third one is the generation. I think those three are the major ones.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can actually look into the routes, generate health, ingest search. So, bare minimum, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: I won't be working with the API directly later on. First, I've kept the script separately, so that if you really want to test it out, so each script, you can actually run it.
Krish NAik: One by one, okay? And you can actually look into the output and in that way, if you wanted. So, that option is also there. So, I'll be just showing you that part once. So, the commands are already there in testing.md, so if I show you my testing.md.
Krish NAik: I've taken everything, from here. So… I think if you guys have done it, the CLI scripts, if you really want to work with CLI scripts.
Krish NAik: So, for example, if I do this one… Okay.
Krish NAik: And… this one… hold on.
Krish NAik: Okay, the first pass is the parsing part.
Krish NAik: Okay, only the past part. If I want to paste it… so, where is my test data? My test data is inside the test data folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, so dark link report.
Krish NAik: If you want to actually save the chunks information.
Krish NAik: Later on, I will be doing that.
Krish NAik: Docling report.
Krish NAik: No, I want to feel good.
Krish NAik: Because, those are simple Python scripts. It's easy to… Debug? Now…
Krish NAik: Can you see, first of all?
Krish NAik: From Hugging Face, we are downloading the layout detection model, because actually, when you are working with scripts, you get better understanding.
Krish NAik: Actually, what has happened?
Krish NAik: Okay? And then, actually, your ulama comes into the picture.
Krish NAik: The same thing that I have done in the Ollama folder, that is. Now, this is a pure Python script. Now, in this script, there are other supports also that I have added, if you want to check out those. So, like, markdown, JSON output, if you want the chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can add the parameter of hyphen hyphen chunks, and that way you can get… if you want a custom directory, like, where you want to save the output, okay, then hyphen hyphen, you can pass the output.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want to skip something in that way, that option is also there. Okay, skip the JSON, so hyphen hyphen. So in that way, I've kept the Python scripts.
Krish NAik: So simply, like, easy to execute for anyone.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want to work with the scripts, it's fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can pass image also. This option is also there.
Krish NAik: But, for now, as we are working with Clear, and this is something like an output that you will get, so, like, I told you, like, it will take time, again, 4 to 5 minutes, 9 pages are there in my local.
Krish NAik: Let's wait for the execution to be completed in my local.
Krish NAik: So, these are standalone scripts.
Krish NAik: That I have kept it. And inside the SLC folder, it's actually the application. The FastAPI application is there.
Krish NAik: Gold flage.
Krish NAik: Because for initially a lot of testing that I've done, it's… that's why I've kept the scripts separately. Then I built the application. So that's why I'm sharing the scripts also.
Krish NAik: Ulam Nanda is asking where I can get any PTA. Say, don't be dependent on mine.
Krish NAik: I showed you, get the DocLink, just search in Google DocLink Technical Report, this is the one that I am using. You can use attention is all you need, that is having more pages, that is the only problem.
Krish NAik: I think I mentioned, you were telling, save zero chance to output, really.
Krish NAik: Actually, I think this one, no, these scripts are actually using the API, or what, because you were getting that Mass API request failed. Mass API means you are hitting the API. That's why I'm thinking.
Krish NAik: Because it should be the ulama.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that, please have a check.
Krish NAik: on that one, that whether in your EMB, if it is none, you should not actually hit the API. Wait, because hitting the API is not our main one.
Krish NAik: And actually, I have the API key, but again, like, if I share, I think entire credits will be gone, my case.
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me just check the script once.
Krish NAik: This is…
Krish NAik: Also, right now, this is fine, I have no issues on this one, but let me check once.
Krish NAik: But really, like, it takes a lot of time.
Krish NAik: That's why even… I don't… We enjoy it a lot.
Krish NAik: Confirm other document, it's a C… it's the same API.
Krish NAik: You are not actually, like, when you are actually executing the script, can you see something like this?
Krish NAik: Because, see, here, when I have executed 9 pages, 81 elements.
Krish NAik: So, it got executed for me, and I think the output will be inside the output folder. Okay, this is a script output.
Krish NAik: So… This one, report.md, the same output with respect to JSON that I have.
Krish NAik: I feel that I'm getting the output, but you were telling the chunks part is not working, okay? So, just wait, let me just,
Krish NAik: what I will do… Come on.
Krish NAik: They will then find us and just wait.
Krish NAik: Let me add that hyphen hyphen jumps.
Krish NAik: Because the chunks part should work.
Krish NAik: Boss…
Krish NAik: Alright, I feel majority. This is…
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just, execute it from my site, and then I will do the confirmation.
Krish NAik: Parsing is working, but chunking is not working. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Shanking is not working, let me just have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Because, in my script, I have actually imported the chunker, so I felt that the chunker should work.
Krish NAik: Because here I can see that doc parser, chunk import, structure over chunking.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I thought that it should work fine.
Krish NAik: But again, let me see…
Krish NAik: Anderson joined the class booth. Wait, fine, I'm sharing the reporting, but a lot of setup is there, Anderson. If you have joined late, I can say that it can be a problem.
Krish NAik: What do you want?
Krish NAik: For how many of you are, like, getting a chance, but I'm doing the testing, just wait, because then I will tell the confirmation. Mataj is telling, it's a little confused, not confusing if you think step by step.
Krish NAik: Because I'm just telling you the scripts I thought about, otherwise directly I can move to the FastAPI app.
Krish NAik: million, so their chunking and other things are not there. It's the… for visualization, I'm shooting, because
Krish NAik: I have not shown last week the GLM OCR visualization. That's why I've showed that part.
Krish NAik: through OLAM. That is that. Now I have started working on the application, the main multimodal RAG application.
Krish NAik: And the first stage is the parsing.
Krish NAik: After parsing, we'll be doing the ingestion.
Krish NAik: And that way, step by step. So the scripts are for that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm just showing you one script, other scripts you guys can explore, because next part, directly, I will start with the Past API application, if you don't want me to check out the scripts.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day.
Krish NAik: They are doing the same thing.
Krish NAik: Yeah, Mantaj is asking, PPDocLayoutv3 is the model which is getting downloaded first, and then the OCR, exactly. First, layout detection, then OCR.
Krish NAik: But another one is initializing the API. Let me see, just wait.
Krish NAik: For me, chunks are working more Taza. Alright.
Krish NAik: Let me see for me also chance that was… because I've done the testing yesterday, and it was working fine.
Krish NAik: After that, I have not really tested the scripts.
Krish NAik: Because on GPUs also, I've done the testing on L4. On L4, it was taking around 3 minutes.
Krish NAik: For this entire, partial.
Krish NAik: I think on T4 also, you guys can do it.
Krish NAik: T4, L4 is fine.
Krish NAik: Minimum 16, gigs.
Krish NAik: What is the Z API? That is the OCR API, if you actually want to use their cloud API ratio, in that case.
Krish NAik: I showed you, no?
Krish NAik: Like, if you go there.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is where, like, Z. This is chat.zai. This is a platform.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here you have that, if you're really working with APIs in that case.
Krish NAik: Malicia.
Krish NAik: Because, really, like, I don't want to…
Krish NAik: one-time parsing I want to do through the Fast API part, then actually I want to go to the retrieval part, because really it's taking a lot of time in my system.
Krish NAik: Because the GPU setup also that I feel which is required. Because many of you might not be doing anything, okay? So I can see, saved 40 chunks, output, docklinkreportchunks.json.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, yes… If I go back here…
Krish NAik: So, I can see text, junk ID, element type, fine, abstract.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see, actually, I'm maintaining the modality, like, each chunk for this is exactly the one fine. Bounding box, caters one.
Krish NAik: Modality, image…
Krish NAik: Okay, modality text. Immediately, I can see that chunking is working. Okay, so please do have a check.
Krish NAik: Because it feels like the channel is working, and there is no issues in that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the chunks, but now I will start the FastAPI application, because, again, the FastAPI application will take 5 minutes, okay? So, let's start with the first part.
Krish NAik: So, for starting your FastAP application in your testing.md, I think you already have that UV run, UVCon, so that script, you can actually go ahead. You can check out the other scripts also, if you're really interested, because the idea was to break down things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once the chunks are there, in the next part, you can actually
Krish NAik: if you are actually doing ingest, ingest will automatically do the parsing, as well as ingestion to the vector DB. It will be making the call for captioning also, so all those things in one shot, which will happen. That part, if you want to test it out, you can do.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because the same things the API will do, so I will switch to the API part right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, then an search script is there if you want to query the vector store for your retrieval.
Krish NAik: Like, and here, multiple filters, I have added it. Like, if you want to look into the chunks only for images, if you want to look into the chunks only for tables and that.
Krish NAik: All right, then the re-ranker backend, exactly which one to use it. So, those options I have already taken in the scripts. Now, I will start the FastAPI application, which is a section 2 of testing.mpt, because all those things that I am telling, I'll be doing it directly on top of the FastAPI application. I think it will be better.
Krish NAik: No, no, don't rerun chunks. Leave it. We will directly execute the FastAPI. People, stop executing the scripts and focus on your FastAPI application right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for the FastAPI application, let me start the server. Okay, so this is simply the command you can copy.
Krish NAik: Okay, because, inside, your doc parser, okay, and SRC is the main one, the module. Inside that, I have my doc parser API. It's the main file, and inside that, the app initialization that we have. Okay, so I will just take this one. So, my main script…
Krish NAik: that I have is inside the SRC folder for my FastAPI application. So what I will do, everybody please leave working with the scripts, because the same thing, the FastAPI routes will do it for you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now let me just start the, Application, first of all.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let me just, take a peer of this one. Bye.
Krish NAik: So here, I have started a FastAPI application. I can open it from my browser.
Krish NAik: So, from my browser, if I try to go here… Okay, so localhost 8000 slash docs, and I can see that the Swagger UI is coming.
Krish NAik: And Quadrant is also running.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can see that quadrant is also running. So this is the document collection. So, first of all, if I check the routes.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please start the FastAP application, link the scripts. Later on, you can actually test each script one by one. Okay, because it will take time.
Krish NAik: The same thing, we can do it in the FastAPI application. The core functionality remains the same.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, let me check the health status, the available APIs here.
Krish NAik: I think, here.
Krish NAik: This is the one… you can test it out.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pinging quadrant and OpenAI key to verify the connectivity, only two tests are there.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the re-ranker backend that I am using is Jenna right now.
Krish NAik: So, for that, we have already configured.
Krish NAik: Then come collections. What is my existing collection?
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is my collection, which is the documents one. So let me delete the collection, and let me create a new one. So I have another API, which is for deleting the collection.
Krish NAik: Do I think I can copy-paste this name?
Krish NAik: Okay, so try it out. You can pass the collection name. So here, in the quadrant UI, you will see that this will be deleted, once I delete it.
Krish NAik: So, here, let me go back, and let me execute it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the execution is done. Deleted is equal to true, collection deleted. If I try to reload this page.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see the collection has been deleted. Fine. Now, let me get back and try to make an ingestion.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the next API is your ingestion.
Krish NAik: Okay, so two ones, so only use the first one right now, ingestion document via file upload.
Krish NAik: Yeah, because PATH is good for locals, so I'll be using it during my deployments also.
Krish NAik: So here, first of all, like, document file, PDF or an image, so let's take a PDF file. I'm taking the same dockling ones on now. Docling underscore report dot PDF. Now, here, collection, just be sure you are passing empty value here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now this option actually helps you to create the collection with your name that you want.
Krish NAik: It will overwrite the default one. So, my default name is the document. So, I'm sending empty value, just be sure. Otherwise, if you pass string, the name of the collection will be string.
Krish NAik: Alright, because in the code, I have kept it that it will be always using documents, that's all.
Krish NAik: Now, the next part is overwrite. I don't want to do any overwriting, so if overwriting is basically already, if you want to, on top of a collection, if you want to delete all the vectors and rewrite anything in that case.
Krish NAik: So, overwriting, false, I don't need it. Maximum chunk tokens, I feel that 512 is bare minimum. I can… otherwise, I can go ahead with 1024. Okay, so 5012, let's go ahead.
Krish NAik: And here, I'm telling image captioning, because this is a document ingestion pipeline. So, for my images.
Krish NAik: Okay, for my… whatever the things, everything, you will be looking into the logs from the terminal when, the API server, so there, I have used LogGuru. So, through LogGuru, I'm tracing all the logs of the application, and I'll be getting it.
Krish NAik: Can you explain about the quadrant part, Methj? Which part?
Krish NAik: In your case, Melind, you have not done it, so you won't see any collections.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, got it telling. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just click on execute, because again, 5 minutes of wait time is there.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here, captioning is also done. Okay, and it will do the ingestion, everything. This is the document ingestion pipeline.
Krish NAik: Alright, execution, now let's look into the terminal.
Krish NAik: So for the terminal, first of all, your layout detection model that needs to be loaded. It's telling that this PDF has total 9 pages.
Krish NAik: I'm using the PiMu PDF for the main page counter. Ulama uses PyPDF, too. So that's why in some cases, I've seen the page numbering is different. That's why I've kept this as a logging, so that, at least for my own clarity.
Krish NAik: both the package return type is sometimes… I've seen the… sometimes the return type is different, so that's why, specifically, I've mentioned it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and right now, I'm not saving the dedicated file in one place. Later on, I will do it. For now, you can see slash var slash folders. So, it's pretty much… I'm creating a temp file.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, right now, I'm just creating a temp fund.
Krish NAik: I'm not creating a persistent one, but later on, I think I can add it.
Krish NAik: How to create a quadrant collection? You don't need to create it. Automatically, it will be created when you are actually hitting it. So, when you are doing it, just be sure you are passing send empty value, this particular checkbox, so automatically it will be created, collection.
Krish NAik: route. You don't have to create it. In my case, I think from my last time, as I was testing, that collection was there.
Krish NAik: Okay, in your case, for everyone, there will be no collections. You'll be… once you hit this API of ingest, it will… the collection will be created for you.
Krish NAik: 404 page not found.
Krish NAik: Read anchor backend switch to JINA, because I think OpenAI have not really checked.
Krish NAik: The… I know that the JINA implementation is full. Other implementations, I've not added yet.
Krish NAik: Rajat is telling laptop is he said, yes, actually, like, when you do these things, even I listen my fans switching on in my Mac, which is very rare.
Krish NAik: So, yes, your laptop will be hot.
Krish NAik: during the PDF docking, will the data leak? If I use it… no, no, no, I'm actually, right now, if you are using everything local, nothing will be leaked in that case. If you are sharing your data with OpenAI, Cloud, Anthropic, or you're using any type of API stuff, then…
Krish NAik: Majorly for, every organization, he'll be hosting this info. Because in my case, see, I can use a good LLM, so, see.
Krish NAik: the more info I need. The Ulama, I'll be running it on GPU. The layout detection model, I'll be running it on my own GPU. I'm not using any APIs.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then later on, you can actually switch to cloud APIs, that is one easier solution, or use a custom self-hosting solution. Okay, and for re-ranking model, that also I can host.
Krish NAik: Everything you can host, you really don't need anything. So, your data only be leaking, actually, for enterprise.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, you will see. Now, this is a part from here I know that the ulama mode using, so again, 4 to 5 minutes, I need to wait.
Krish NAik: Let's wait. In the meantime. Everybody, please start the ingestion part, this is the first thing, because the same thing that I'll be replicating it.
Krish NAik: In… There, what I saw. Enlighten, that's it.
Krish NAik: Zoom.us, 60%.
Krish NAik: Yes, Amar, it means that there are no collections.
Krish NAik: If you are getting a blank list, it means no collections.
Krish NAik: Raul is telling internal server error, fine.
Krish NAik: Maintenance server error, if the ulama worked, I think it should work in your case also, so…
Krish NAik: Just wait. Rishabh is saying Fast API is not working. It means the Swagger UI is not coming up, Rishabh?
Krish NAik: Or, like, what is the issue?
Krish NAik: Swagger UI is not opening.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'll be looking into that. Don't worry.
Krish NAik: I'll be taking the route, don't worry, once…
Krish NAik: The core things, the core testing part, once we have done it.
Krish NAik: Now, internal server error, because of which one? Ingest, line number 177.
Krish NAik: Line number 177, what is there? Let me see.
Krish NAik: This is… this is executing your entire ingestion pipeline.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here, just look into my terminal.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: look into my terminal, everyone. See, first of all, the parsing is done. 9 pages, 81 elements, total 35 chance. Now, you can see, I'm making call to GPT-40 for image captioning. So, these are the calls.
Krish NAik: Okay? Of, the one. So finally, the enrichment is, so enrichment of… because, this is the phase where actually, like, we…
Krish NAik: It creates structure captioning, so because of that. So, enriched, total output that you are actually getting is 3 image, 4 tables, okay, 2 algorithms.
Krish NAik: Based on that, like, whatever we got.
Krish NAik: Okay? You can see the document. So, right now, last time I deleted, upset it 35 points to document. So, now if I do the verification, the same thing that you guys will see that the collection is available.
Krish NAik: So it means that, yes, so SPART, because this is a hybrid search.
Krish NAik: So, and text and then. So, both the things are available right now. I can see that they are working fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for how many of you, this executed? If this, the documentation pipeline doesn't execute, then nothing that we can actually, go ahead and, like, test out the other things also.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Use 1536 in my code, I've used 1536. Don't use 3072.
Krish NAik: Using a bigger model is not the priority.
Krish NAik: The first part should execute.
Krish NAik: Because if there is some issue with respect to parsing, I can say that, yes.
Krish NAik: there, can be some type of problems, not major, but yes, problems can be…
Krish NAik: Because… Your ingestion will be done, then only the embeddings, and then only we can actually do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, and open host and slash docs.
Krish NAik: Because for me, then I can actually explore the generate part. In the generate part, you will see that,
Krish NAik: the schema design, basically, here, if we want to pass a custom system prompt, so for that, also, I've given the option this time. Okay, but again, like, this is not important.
Krish NAik: So, I'll be using the default one, which is in my script. I'll be deleting this one. Filter modality, if you want to filter by only table images, in that case, it is required.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think let me pass.
Krish NAik: Okay, and let me ask a question here, and let me see that. I will be asking a question from the table, okay? So, let's go here.
Krish NAik: To the table part.
Krish NAik: Okay, image, I will ask, first of all, I think.
Krish NAik: Fine images are there, table is there. Now here, like, M3 Max Intel Xeon Fine. So, something like this, let me just…
Krish NAik: Generate one push, and… then in that case, I think,
Krish NAik: Let me just delete the string.
Krish NAik: I've taken the screenshot.
Krish NAik: Fine, just wait, let me get the question.
Krish NAik: Quadrant API is not required. We are doing Quadrant local, Docker is running.
Krish NAik: Well, please have a check.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I can see that I'm getting the response.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, okay, now see, if you really try to analyze this, what we have done, so please look into my screen, leave your work right now.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a question that I have asked, okay, like, what is the pages for the PDF web backup on Intel Xeon with 16 threads? You can see, actually, pretty much one, and this question is based on this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, Intel Xeon, exactly 16 core, the TTS backend is there. Okay, so when I actually go back here, you will see that, okay, the output is coming, what is the pages per second?
Krish NAik: Here, it's telling the throughput is, so here, at the end of the day, can you see that I don't have enough information to actually answer?
Krish NAik: Just try to analyze this one.
Krish NAik: How we are getting the response.
Krish NAik: Because, though, explicitly it is not available in a direct context, because the information which is available, I am actually sending, and actually, this is a chunk.
Krish NAik: This is the summary.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in this summary, if you actually look into
Krish NAik: the result, because this part, because, see, here I am doing captioning, and if my captions are not good, really.
Krish NAik: Then what is the problem that we do face?
Krish NAik: So, TTS was second. With the PDM backend, I can say for Intel is, like, 1.57.
Krish NAik: Okay, 1.57 should be the answer, but really, in my captions, somehow, that particular information is missing.
Krish NAik: Okay, I feel that, yes, 1.57, this information is actually missing. It means that somehow I need to work. Now, let me try with a different question. And, see, now this is the summary for the table. If you look into the modality, the modality is actually the table.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, I will test out with some other questions, because where the system fails, let's focus. Because I know that where the system will pass directly, and I can pass such questions, but this is really important, because it's not your mistake.
Krish NAik: Okay, you have to understand, because captioning is not really up to the mark, though it has kept most of the information, but somehow, that 16 core with that, that information of 1.5, I feel that it is missing.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, let's try to change the cushion a little bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, let's, reduce the number of threads, and let me see whether this information is there or not.
Krish NAik: So, how many threads was the other option 4? Let's try to pass 4.
Krish NAik: Because when it is failing, it's, like, really, you have to understand that part, okay? So, I got the response.
Krish NAik: See, again, it's telling that I don't have enough information. It means that, again, the captioning failed. Now, I will be changing little bit the question, because I know that, yes, this information, both is not available here.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Now, some hair, let me take that. I'll be, just changing a little bit the question.
Krish NAik: Let's take, I think somewhere from this one. Because exactly, because of captioning, how the system fails, it's…
Krish NAik: A really interesting to see.
Krish NAik: Because from the caption, Let's look into the memory part once.
Krish NAik: Because I know that in the caption, that information is there, but actually, it is not, getting that information.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in the meantime, let me look into the logs also once.
Krish NAik: Because the final result after re-ranking, I can see that the re-ranker is working really, really great. There is no issue with the re-ranker, because the first chunk is actually the chunk from where I am asking the question.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Now, this is actually the table, and I was asking the question from the tables.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so a little bit late change.
Krish NAik: And let me see. Because really, like, this is a little bit dynamic part, because when you'll be working, I feel that GPT-40 really doesn't work so great on this one. Because of that, even I was planning to change the model with the structure a little bit.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, let me ask a question similarly from the table.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you will see that this time, it will be working, okay? Now, on Intel Zion, which backend provides higher pages at 16 threads? Okay? Now, this portion. Now, when I look into this portion, you can see that, yes, I'm getting the response.
Krish NAik: But again, at the end of the day, every time I have feel that it's getting added, I don't have enough information, but actually, I feel that this is the context which is being passed.
Krish NAik: But really, like, why this issue is coming?
Krish NAik: Because, really, most of the times.
Krish NAik: I can do a re-injection, but again, somehow… because, the chunk is actually correct, but within that chunk, the information that I think… because if you look into the re-ranking results, I can say the re-ranking is working perfectly fine, but the return time.
Krish NAik: Yes, the default prompt is there, in the generate.
Krish NAik: Script, Aviation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… We're looking.
Krish NAik: Because sometimes, okay, I will just try one more.
Krish NAik: Because few testing that I fielded,
Krish NAik: Really on top of… Because the return type, but the result on this one is not working.
Krish NAik: I can change the model to a better one, but GPT-4.0 initial testing, it was actually giving me all the results correctly.
Krish NAik: exact PTS values, it's not able to pay.
Krish NAik: Let me check the…
Krish NAik: Because every time, why? It's throwing that part.
Krish NAik: Because this result can be different for everyone.
Krish NAik: How many of you… the ingestion part is done, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Because for me, really, I was…
Krish NAik: Okay? Because if I try to make a generic query much more.
Krish NAik: Okay, so something like this. Because two machines were there, let me try to do a comparison. Compare TTS between M3 Max and Intel Geon. Let me check, like, this one.
Krish NAik: Because, again, the table data is the most one, okay? So, the return type, I can say that.
Krish NAik: The time-to-time solution at 16th rate is 92 seconds, there I'm getting response. This is page number 5, because you will get also exactly which page number from the PDF, because this is…
Krish NAik: The structure of our chunking, you get the entire information. Page fib, 17 chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the modality table, all right. But again, okay. Now, what I will do, I'll be, trying to perform a re-injection right now.
Krish NAik: I feel that reagion is not required, we can move to the GPU part.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I can see that, yes, in some cases it's failing, in some cases it's working. It means that I need better captioning from the GPT-4.
Krish NAik: I can query like you, showing… yeah, yes, you can ask questions from the tables directly. So, for example, if I ask, simple questions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… how many cores are there in Apple M3 Max?
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think Apple M3.
Krish NAik: Max, okay, so this is the name. Directly, try to just ask question, Apple M3 Max, 16 cores.
Krish NAik: So, let's see, like, what is the result?
Krish NAik: Okay, because I can see here…
Krish NAik: because of this particular chunk, I'll field at the information somehow. Okay, now, what I will do, I will just delete the collection, and I will try to perform a re-injection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Now you will see that, again, it will change. It can actually give response to three of the things.
Krish NAik: And a few of the things will start working. Let me just try to perform this one.
Krish NAik: Because this part is not really static, it's dynamic, because of the API call.
Krish NAik: But, the idea is to make a structure. I have kept that for every GPT4O generated. The minimum number of tokens should be 512. Okay? So, let me just pass once more, and let me just, do a re-injation part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so others can let me know that in your case, if you are trying to ask a question from the table, it's working or not.
Krish NAik: Rajat, working, everybody please let me know. Because, first of all, see, the API response should be up and working. If you are getting red, I don't have enough context, but your result of the re-ranker should be good. It means that re-ranking is working fine. Then, later on, we can actually handle things in caption.
Krish NAik: Please let me know that part.
Krish NAik: Pass, but embedding is failing. Why emitting is failing? Just be sure you are using text embedding 3 small with 1536 dimension.
Krish NAik: If you are working with that, I don't feel that you will be having any problems.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I will be doing a rechunking, okay, and then, like, entirely a re-in session, and this time I will ask… be asking a few of the questions which it actually fit.
Krish NAik: Now, this is one part which I feel that, this is one of the major bottlenecks if you are actually going ahead with layout detection. Because really, like, in most of the demos and other places, they will be generating a sh…
Krish NAik: one or two-liner caption. But I feel that one or two-liner caption really doesn't help. You need more and more details. So, probably, what is the flow? Like, whenever you were doing the captioning, you have to think from table perspective, from formula perspective, from diagram perspective.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why. So, like, you have to, create much more detailed, caption, and that way, I feel that the retrieval will always be better.
Krish NAik: But, in some cases. So, first of all, check the API is responding correctly.
Krish NAik: Okay, because text-related answer, I know it will work. So directly, I want to put my focus very specifically on tables and images.
Krish NAik: Once the re-ingestion is done, okay, so if I switch back to the terminal… Hmm…
Krish NAik: The captioning is done by AI. Exactly correct.
Krish NAik: pollute an image there. Melinda, if you want to ask a question related, in the document ingestion pipeline, pass an image.
Krish NAik: Install the dependencies, Poonam, You are not installed JLM OCR layout, please do the installation.
Krish NAik: In PyProject.2ML, you have that.
Krish NAik: If you have done that, it should work.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because, yes, the application is somehow… don't worry, because I think in the
Krish NAik: You have a Dockerfile also, like, the entire infra, you can actually launch it through Dockerfile rather than doing it separately. That, I'll be showing it in the Lightning AI part, but let me just show you, like, here, how captioning matters. In some cases, really, it works, in some cases, it might fail.
Krish NAik: So, that particular…
Krish NAik: Because this part, I feel that, a little bit of structured output that we need to work on.
Krish NAik: And that part, tomorrow I'll be showing you exactly the improvement part.
Krish NAik: Because the GLM OCR is captured, the layout detection is also captured.
Krish NAik: How many of you are getting the response from the API? You can… actually, like, I have not done the testing with the text modality, but you can do a testing with that also.
Krish NAik: And let me know that, are you getting any responses?
Krish NAik: How many of you are getting the response from slash generate API?
Krish NAik: Modality count?
Krish NAik: I'm getting modality count, please check your, see. If you want to do a visual one, I will show you the visual, but right now I have deleted the collection. Go inside your collection and check for the modality.
Krish NAik: You are getting collection, source file, modality count, latency, name.
Krish NAik: Alright, what is filter modality? Filter modality, it means that, Mitesh, if you want to only, look into the table chunks, only if you want to look into the image chunks, only if you want to look into the formula chunks.
Krish NAik: That is the filter modality.
Krish NAik: It gives you, like, if you want to do a filtration based on modalities, that option is also available.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I'm doing a re-injection, so once that is done, then I'll be shown.
Krish NAik: The generate API is working, Rajat has confirmed. Alright, what about others?
Krish NAik: For how many of you, the API is working, the generate API?
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: I am changing the model to GPT-5. Okay, alright, you can change the model. No issues.
Krish NAik: even I was planning to change that. But,
Krish NAik: Because, yeah, that's what I want to show you, like, this is one place where I feel that if the quality of captioning for tables and images are really not good, it can create a problem.
Krish NAik: In some cases it works, in some cases it fails.
Krish NAik: Now you can see the OCR API request, HTTP connection pool, and localhost 11434. This is from Olama data I'm getting, actually.
Krish NAik: It means that my RAM usage is really high.
Krish NAik: Then only this, fail happens.
Krish NAik: Others can actually change the LLM to GPT, some other, whichever you need.
Krish NAik: Raul is asking, are we uploading the PDF file? Yes, we'll be uploading the PDF file only.
Krish NAik: JSON was just for visualization.
Krish NAik: And, like, if I show you the return type of the API,
Krish NAik: Like, alright, I have done that, but last time, like, you'll be getting something like this in your final user.
Krish NAik: Okay, your main query with answer, with your main sources.
Krish NAik: Rahul is asking, API mass API request is coming. Actually, if you're getting Chinese characters, it means that we… you are hitting the API to, Z, Zed Cloud API, I feel that.
Krish NAik: It should not be Mars API, because,
Krish NAik: If you have done the configuration in your .env, otherwise, you can hardcode it also, like, the hardcoding part needs to be done in your config.py.
Krish NAik: But in our config.py, if you, look into, like, the default parser is cloud, then change it to alarm. This is the other way around.
Krish NAik: Because here, it's by default cloud, but I know that from my ANUV file, it will pick up.
Krish NAik: Okay, Raul, so you can, like, check this part once.
Krish NAik: Open config.py, which is inside SRC doc parser.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So please have a check on this one, and just change this cloud tool alarm.
Krish NAik: If you are feeling that, then also. Because by default, it reads the ENV file.
Krish NAik: You can see how the application settings are loaded from the .env file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, I can see the upset is done. Okay, so now, like, I can know that I can start making, questions. Okay, so simple.
Krish NAik: Based on that. So, similarly, this LLM model, if you feel that… if you want to update it, you can update it from here also. The GPT-4O, try to take a better model.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, always remember, these are the default settings in config.py. If you want, you can change it at any point of time.
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: Let me go back to the, one. Okay, so from the table, fine, I will try to ask.
Krish NAik: some question from the image also. I feel that images are also important.
Krish NAik: Ocr analyst says, okay, so something like, let me take one…
Krish NAik: And let me see that whether it works or not. Like, a little bit of arrangement if it can be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… This will actually help me to understand that whether this is working on…
Krish NAik: So, share, how many codes?
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, according to the…
Krish NAik: image, I have asked a question, let me see.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I can see that the, arrange the following steps in order. This was the thing that I asked. OCR, table structure layout, and I can see that, source page 3, the steps are in, in order. Okay, OCR, layout analysis, table structure, all right.
Krish NAik: So I can see that, yes. Can you see that the modality is image?
Krish NAik: Yes, please let me know, because here I can see that, yes, the response is coming fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is actually a question, like, I can say that we asked from the image. So, this is… the image is in page 3. Okay, so you can get a detailed page 3 and probably the 8 chunk in total. So, from the captions, I feel that it's getting.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's try to ask a question.
Krish NAik: from the image, assembly results.
Krish NAik: Alright. Assembly results before that. This is a little bit of flu understanding, that's the question that I'm trying to ask.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me take, like,
Krish NAik: Little bit of low understanding part.
Krish NAik: These are image-based questions, really, that I am, passing right now.
Krish NAik: And I feel that, is analyze the table structure, okay, based on the response.
Krish NAik: analyze the table structure. Okay, this is the table structure. So I can see that the flow understanding, because I feel that the captions which are generated for the image, they are really working good. There is no, like,
Krish NAik: issues and that, okay? Now, let me try to… Pass some other questions.
Krish NAik: Because the image modality is working fine, I will text with the table modality after this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, if you look into, describe the full pipeline, I can see that this is coming, and can you see, again, the mortality has been picked up as an image? See, right now.
Krish NAik: During multimodal rack, first of all, test that the table images are working. That is the first priority. Text will work. Anything you ask from the normal text part, there won't be any type of problem. But I can say that my re-anchor is working exactly the fine.
Krish NAik: Because this is my expectations, so, and based on that, I can say that yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody, because the image modality part is, working fine, I can say.
Krish NAik: Now, with respect to a little bit reasoning on top of tables that we can do.
Krish NAik: Alright,
Krish NAik: Now, let me try to ask, because the table part, I feel that, and most of the times, no, the tables part, it fails. So probably switching to a better LLM, that is one option, but in some cases. So, always try to analyze the results.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please do have a check.
Krish NAik: No, don't.
Krish NAik: Let's try to take a cross-CPU comparison, in that case. From the tables, let me try to take…
Krish NAik: Okay, so which CPU shows a larger improvement in TTS when increasing the threads from native backend? I think removing the brackets will be much better. I don't need the brackets.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is actually a question, with respect to the table, just like last time I have asked it. Okay, now let me see that in my context.
Krish NAik: Okay, the CPU shows a larger improvement in TTS when increasing the threads native, alright? This is page number 5, so I'm getting the response from the table, and my re-ranking, the first chunk that is coming is the modalities table. Everybody, please check, because, see, I am doing the testing.
Krish NAik: Till the time you don't do the test, you won't really understand. Everybody, please do the testing.
Krish NAik: Don't go with bigger documents. Please always go with smaller documents, okay? Now, let's try to ask a little bit more questions from that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this question is fine, which should be used? Let's try to change. So, there were two CPUs, the Apple M3 Mats and the Intel Xeon. So, which one is more efficient on the PDF back end? Okay, the PDFM, for PDFs which is used. Now, let me see the response here.
Krish NAik: Am I getting I don't have any enough? Okay, now. Last time, it was not working, but this time. So it's telling the Intel Xeon is more memory efficient for PDF 2.42GB of memory compared, this one. So, memory efficient, if you look here.
Krish NAik: From the tables.
Krish NAik: to dot… Mmm…
Krish NAik: All right, because the PDF backend, 2.42. So I can say that, yes, the results are correct, it's not showing anything, like, misleading.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please try to do the testing, because right now, it's your job. Very specifically, put the focus on tables and images, everyone.
Krish NAik: How many of you are doing the testing parallelly?
Krish NAik: You can ask any type of questions.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, everybody in the chat.
Krish NAik: I think so.
Krish NAik: So I can say majorly that right now, previously, like, the table was not being handled.
Krish NAik: But, this time I feel that okay. Last time, also, I think I passed this question.
Krish NAik: how much memory? Let me see working or not. The native MN backend uses 16 thread with 6.2GB memory. Modality table. So, majorly, I can see that
Krish NAik: The core pipeline, the functionality was working fine.
Krish NAik: Motada is telling you, after changing to 5.4, the results are better. For sure, I know that that is one of the bottlenecks here. That's why I'm telling you, that's why I performed a re-injection, just to show you that it's working. But remember.
Krish NAik: Really, like, the main focus will be your retrieval part also, with re-rank.
Krish NAik: Because in my re-ranking, I can actually see that the modality table, it is coming in the first place.
Krish NAik: So I feel that, yeah, it's better.
Krish NAik: Because last time, in the chunk, so much information was not there. So, because of that, this time, the LLM has generated more information.
Krish NAik: Because of that, I can say that, yes, the response is coming. Fine.
Krish NAik: All right, see, now I will take that, okay, you guys do more testing, because here I will, switch the LLM then to 5.4, and, like, I think when I'll be discussing the code of image captioning, that file you can improve much better.
Krish NAik: It means that if you want to… see, right now, these are the total number of tokens that I'm keeping. It means that this entire summary
Krish NAik: is generated by GPT-4. So, switch to a better LLM, and if you feel that, try to keep not only a summary, try to keep all the details about the table if you want. That part is also fine.
Krish NAik: But it should maintain the maximum chunk size, which is 512 in our case. You can increase it to 1024. Now, those are the parameters that you can actually play with, because I know that the core functionality is working.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys, because now in the next phase, I will start with the GPU setup right now.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I can take a few questions, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I will start the part with the… yes, I think I can start sharing my screen.
Krish NAik: Alright, Rahul, you were facing, I think, the API issue? Yes.
Rahul Parihar: So Paul, let me share my screen.
Krish NAik: Do you want to share more with me?
Krish NAik: Alright, I will add you to panelist.
Krish NAik: Only one question I'm taking. After that, I will start with GPU.
Krish NAik: Because the GPU setup is really, really easy, so…
Krish NAik: If I do it, I know that after the class, you guys will spend the time.
Krish NAik: In the book.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rahul Parihar: So, so, in the config.config, the change is there, olama.
Rahul Parihar: In environment, I've removed the Z part.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, keep that, keep that. Why are you agree? Keep that, but keep it to none.
Krish NAik: Keep it to none.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, just, okay, just commented it out, or keep it on none.
Krish NAik: Capital… no, no, don't… You keep the committee.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, yeah, whatever. You know, we are anywhere not using it, right?
Rahul Parihar: No, not.
Krish NAik: But it will actually read the file, whether it is there or not, that's why.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, okay.
Krish NAik: The logic, that's why N, capital, keep it the first N of none.
Rahul Parihar: Got it. And then, you know, just the quadrant.
Krish NAik: This is your Docker.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah… Yeah… Yeah, this is my, and Docker is running here local.
Krish NAik: Yes, correct.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: You can reload this page if you want.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Rahul Parihar: Fair enough. Now… I'm reload… I'm just restarting the server.
Rahul Parihar: But I'm keep getting that Chinese, you know, letter.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, CCC, whenever you are starting the server, in the longest check, it's telling you, starting doc parser API, and after that, parser is… till now, parser is equal to cloud.
Rahul Parihar: Oh…
Krish NAik: That's why, no, go back to your .env.
Krish NAik: One thing, okay, keep that, none can make it capital.
Krish NAik: the first none, and it's… no, no, no, no, only the normal nun, yes, okay? Ctrl-S,
Krish NAik: Okay, try to, restart.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want, you can change it in config.py file also.
Krish NAik: Go back to, config.py, that is, config.py.
Krish NAik: Let's remove cloud and add their roles.
Krish NAik: Open your… This one, what happened? Connection issues, or what?
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, I kind of can hear you, but… What happened?
Krish NAik: Okay, open config.py. I think inside the SRC folder, you have the config.py, open.file.
Rahul Parihar: I don't know what happened, my system got… All of them.
Krish NAik: It happens. When you run, models locally, it happens, it's common.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, now it's back, okay.
Krish NAik: Oh, nice.
Rahul Parihar: I don't know what happened. So, config.yml…
Krish NAik: Yeah, so there you have already changed it to Ollama. So I think we are good to go. Now, do a Ctrl-S and try to run the Fast API. Let me see.
Krish NAik: Because in the Fast API, it should tell you, like, what is the backend that's like.
Krish NAik: Kill the existing, terminals.
Rahul Parihar: I don't know what happened.
Krish NAik: it happens, see, I know the RAM usage really, like, fluctuates a lot.
Krish NAik: Because Ulama is running, that takes RAM. Docker is running, that takes RAM. Models that are running that takes RAM, everything.
Krish NAik: Method is telling for 3-page documents, fine. People, like, I know that CPU inferencing is fine. If it is not working, leave it. In GPU, for sure, it will work. So just be sure you have your Lightning AI accounts, so that we can start after this part. Everybody will be getting the response, don't worry.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, I'm doing…
Krish NAik: You already have… .
Rahul Parihar: I'm loading the layout also, because it has the torch.
Rahul Parihar: I don't need to run the quadrant.
Rahul Parihar: And now I'm going to just run the…
Rahul Parihar: There is that one, for unicorns.
Krish NAik: Below that, below that.
Krish NAik: Okay, you are opening read.md, open, testing.md, that in section 2, huh?
Krish NAik: Previously, I think. This is the… this is the doc parser API, yeah, this is the only command.
Krish NAik: Rajak will be doing it in cloud GPUs, not in your local.
Krish NAik: Lightning AI account, if you have no issues. That's why it would last last week. Create your Lightning AI account, you'll be getting 15 credits. That is more than enough.
Rahul Parihar: Collection name in the environment is not there.
Rahul Parihar: Please use the example.
Rahul Parihar: So why don't…
Krish NAik: I think, by default, it is documents.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, there is as a document.
Krish NAik: If it is there, like, not sure, because somehow… Let's documentage there.
Rahul Parihar: Whilst the pre-example has been…
Krish NAik: No, that is a duplication one, not to worry about.
Krish NAik: Everyone, please log in into your Lightning AI account, okay? And you can launch a machine of an L4.
Krish NAik: others, like, in the meantime, as I'm looking into his issue.
Rahul Parihar: What should I do now? So this is…
Rahul Parihar: I believe the… and .env is not getting loaded properly, is that a problem? I've unsat the…
Krish NAik: Like, Really linked.
Rahul Parihar: URL… let me unset that.
Krish NAik: Because… If you're UNB, I feel that it is in the correct place.
Krish NAik: And you are in which folder? Right now, you are in the multimodal rag folder only. From there, you are executing. So, everything is correct. I cannot see anything. Quadrant URL, it is not… because in that case, quadrant URL, it is HTTP localhost. It will be picking up.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, so I have commented this part, that's why.
Krish NAik: Which part you have commented?
Rahul Parihar: config.pyazz.
Rahul Parihar: API…
Krish NAik: Back-end is the KL2 alone, okay?
Rahul Parihar: weapons.
Krish NAik: Done. I think this was… you were looking for it.
Rahul Parihar: It should work now, right?
Krish NAik: Hmm, now it should work. No, that was the problem. Last time, parser was equal to cloud.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you can do the testing. In the meantime, let me continue with the rest of this.
Rahul Parihar: Thanks, thanks, I'll test it. Thank you well.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys, now let's start with our GPU. Nothing in local for anybody for whom it was not working, great, not to worry about. We will do it now in cloud.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just, let me just open mine.
Krish NAik: We have a Lightning AI website, and I think…
Krish NAik: UK.
Krish NAik: I think, yes. So, everybody, please, just switch on to your Lightning AI.
Krish NAik: Okay? And then I'll be launching a machine.
Krish NAik: Once my login is done, I will launch a new studio. In that studio, I'll be taking a GPU, okay? I'll be switching off the interruptible, this option.
Krish NAik: And I'll be selecting L4.
Krish NAik: Okay, till this point, you guys are ready, let me know, then I will launch it.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody, I think everybody has Lightning AI accounts. Last… to last week, I told.
Krish NAik: It will be image, it will… Mitesh, you can pass image, you can pass table, You can pass formula.
Krish NAik: Those are the filter modality values that you can play with.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: People for whom nothing worked directly come to this part. Later on, you can explore the CPU things. In your system, it can be a problem, but please.
Krish NAik: Because from now, we'll switch to this part.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please open your Lightning AI accounts.
Krish NAik: I would think everybody has Lightning AI account. In the last class already, I told, use your operation last to last week. It has been 2 weeks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here, I'll be launching a machine. Please let me know that
Krish NAik: This is my configuration, and please use the same configuration. I'll be using an L4,
Krish NAik: From GCP, GCP is cheaper in this case.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I feel that for our
Krish NAik: Main practical, it will be more than enough.
Krish NAik: Guys, please let me know how you guys opened the Lightning AI page.
Krish NAik: Melaine the Dan. What about others? Everybody, please let me know, because there are pretty much inactivity, I can say.
Krish NAik: Everybody, like, whoever CPU is not working, please open the Lightning AI page.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: What should be the studio type? That only I'm selecting. No, see. Studio type, AI development. Okay? AI development, then coming to Machine. Click on Machine, you will be getting CPU by default, click on GP. Switch off this option of interruptible.
Krish NAik: Okay? Interruptible instances are generally cheaper, but if it breaks in between your work, it becomes a problem, okay? Now, select L4 from here, L4.
Krish NAik: Till this point, can I proceed?
Krish NAik: Everybody, can I proceed?
Krish NAik: Abhishek is telling, please, once again.
Krish NAik: See, guys, I'll be creating a new studio right now, okay? So this is my homepage.
Krish NAik: I'll be clicking on this one, New Studio, then I will click on AI Development.
Krish NAik: Then I'll be clicking on Machines, then I'll be clicking on GPU, then I'll be clicking on L4.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I'll be switching off this option of interrupting.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Can I proceed? Let me… now I will click Launch, okay? So I will just confirm.
Krish NAik: So, one L4, L4 GPU does. Okay, and I will click on start. This process, I'm not going to… because, like, again, I don't want to repeat.
Krish NAik: I think for everybody it is done. Can I click on start?
Krish NAik: Alright, I've clicked on start, now the studio will start.
Krish NAik: Once the studio is up, and you will see this here green color, then we will proceed.
Krish NAik: Okay, just wait.
Krish NAik: Wait time was… One to two minutes, so we have to wait.
Krish NAik: They are now offering Copilot. It was not there two weeks back, okay.
Krish NAik: Claude also looking… because, I generally love Lightning AI, just because Docker is installed, AWS, CLI is installed, most of the things as a developer which I need comes very installed.
Krish NAik: So my major R&D, my personal R&D, I do it here only.
Krish NAik: And the best thing is, within one click, I can switch back to a CP.
Krish NAik: So, that is the… one of the best things, where in cloud, it is not possible only.
Krish NAik: Alright, green color I saw, now green color, so pretty much done. The first thing, do, okay, can you see this SSH here?
Krish NAik: SSH, here, on the top. Let me try to make the font a little bit bigger. Can you see SSH?
Krish NAik: Okay, it depends upon the instance, Rajat, leave it, okay? Can you see SSH? I'll be connecting via SSH, okay? So I will click on this option, connect via SSH. Okay, I will copy this command.
Krish NAik: And then I will open my, terminal, and I will paste it, and I will hit enter.
Krish NAik: So I'm connected to the instance, and now if I do an NVIDIA-SMI, I do have an L4.
Krish NAik: Yeah, you can see an L4GP.
Krish NAik: Because I am not going to use that one majorly, I work with terminals, so you guys also be good in terminals.
Krish NAik: please do SSH.
Krish NAik: The option is there, you have to just click there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, Mac.
Krish NAik: Linux, Windows, you can see, partial admin session to start an SSH, something like that.
Krish NAik: Once the SSH part is done, and you really don't need to switch on here, Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know that SSH is working for you or not.
Krish NAik: If SSH is not working, simply use the terminal. Okay, so here also you can work with terminal. You can go click in these three dots, you can click on Terminal.
Krish NAik: Okay? That is also fine, I have no issues.
Krish NAik: whichever way, because I really, prefer working… this is much faster. The UI is a little bit laggy, that I feel.
Krish NAik: Okay, and see, right now, if I'm going ahead, so…
Krish NAik: Can you see here? Docker is already installed?
Krish NAik: That is the benefit. I have Docker, even, I think, AWS is also there. In most of the instances, they will get pre-installed everything.
Krish NAik: AWS CLI is also there, so as a developer, I know that majorly, my deployments, it will be working fine here.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Can I proceed with the next part?
Krish NAik: for everybody, like, if SSH, or use that part. Whichever way, fine. Alright, now I'm going to clone my report. I will add the command git clone. Okay, and let's get back to the repo.
Krish NAik: Where is the GitHub, GitHub, GitHub, GitHub, GitHub, yeah. This is my GitHub. I will go here, I will copy this, https.git link, and I will paste it here.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now the code came in my machine.
Krish NAik: Then I will go, and I will go inside the folder Multimodal RAG.
Krish NAik: why you will upload it, Mitesh? You have the cloning option that's better, you can actually upload it. So, in that case, what you can do, just for you, I am telling.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… if you want to upload it, then create a, like, the zip file will be downloaded, download the zip, okay? Then go into Team SpaceDrive.
Krish NAik: upload it from your add data option comes, like, this studio, select the studio.
Krish NAik: Okay, and add data. So here you can upload. In the last class, I showed you how to upload things.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: I'm going too fast.
Krish NAik: Till which point you guys have done it.
Krish NAik: I've just created the machine, I have set up the SSH, and I have simply done the Git clone. Abhishek cloned all right, cloning done.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, like, I can wait 2-3 minutes.
Krish NAik: Cloning done? Cloning done? Great.
Krish NAik: After cloning is done, go into the multimodal rack folder.
Krish NAik: You will see, by default, The master branch will be there.
Krish NAik: Okay, till this point, how many of you can see?
Krish NAik: Please let me know. And others, like, who are stuck in between where you guys are stuck.
Krish NAik: Because this tip is pretty much simple.
Krish NAik: Click, click, click, done.
Krish NAik: Let me know for others, because this part I want everybody. There is no local dependency, and you guys can do everything.
Krish NAik: Yeah, Rahul, till which point?
Krish NAik: Yes, after that, you got that commando, SSH. Copy that the last part. Okay, and paste it.
Krish NAik: add sudo. If you're not getting the permission, add sudo.
Krish NAik: Because permission denied problem, nothing I can do, it's your system level only, no?
Krish NAik: Because you should have the permissions.
Krish NAik: I'm inside the multimodal folder. See, if I show it here, I'm inside this folder.
Krish NAik: this. Can you see the multimodal drag? I need to go inside this folder to execute my project.
Krish NAik: Abhishek, I'm inside this multimodal rack folder from the terminal. I've done simple CD multimodal rack, nothing else.
Krish NAik: If you guys don't want to use the local, then please execute the command from here, git clone, okay? That is also fine, I have no issues, whichever way you do it.
Krish NAik: from this terminal, directly from EY, Okay? Or from your local.
Krish NAik: Let me know, can I proceed to the next step?
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. Now I will get… Switch.
Krish NAik: deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the other branch that I have, so I will be switching to this branch.
Krish NAik: Alright, git switch deployment. I think the… everybody should know Git commands, pretty much switching a branch, okay? So now, my branch has changed from master to deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you will see that, right now you'll be having some more files, more Docker files, and other things.
Krish NAik: Let me know.
Krish NAik: And I have… inside that, you have a lightning underscore AI underscore deploy file. You can open the Markdown file, and you can copy-paste the commands.
Krish NAik: Okay, or the same thing you can do in your local laws.
Krish NAik: in your local, like, if you actually switch it to a different branch. So, for example, here also, the same thing that can be done. Okay, just git.
Krish NAik: Switch, deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay? And now, if I go to VS Code, I think I'll be getting that. So, in whichever way, immediately the commands are there, so if you open the Lightning and deploy.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: it'll be getting the commands that I'll be executing. Like, NVIDIA, if an SMI chatting, I have.
Krish NAik: this part, git clone, CD multimodal rag, you have done it. Now you need the environment file.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, because I don't have the .env file here, what I will do, I will open my ENV, I will copy-paste Ctrl-C, and paste it where, in the other one, here.
Krish NAik: So, here, let me just create a file.env. Everybody, please create a .env file here.
Krish NAik: Okay? And done. Just paste the same thing that you have done in local. Nothing else.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, till now, what are the steps that I have done? I have done SSH. After SSH, I have done CD.
Krish NAik: Okay? After CD, I have done switching of the branch.
Krish NAik: After switching off the branch, I have just created a .env file and pasted the same thing.
Krish NAik: From my local to them.
Krish NAik: Please let me know that,
Krish NAik: Till this point, once you guys are done, then I will continue with the next steps.
Krish NAik: You just need to create the .env file.
Krish NAik: I just created the .env file.
Krish NAik: SSH issue is resolved, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: If you have done SSH, after SSH, you have to go into the multimodal rack folder, do a CD. After that, just do a git switch deployment, change the branch from your master to deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, you have not done git clone, then do git clone also, yeah.
Krish NAik: For how many of you this step is done, please let me know. You have… you guys have created the .env file. Just copy-paste the same thing from your local to here.
Krish NAik: You can use nano, VI, I have no issues, whichever text editors you want to use.
Krish NAik: Sandy telling Dan, what about others? Please provide a confirmation. At the ENV file, you will see, the ENV file here.
Krish NAik: Copy-paste from… directly copy-paste. That's the same thing that I did, no?
Krish NAik: I went, I copy-paste the entire thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then just create a file here. Okay, like, click on the plus sign. Just be sure it is in the root directory.
Krish NAik: Not inside any folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, it has to be inside the multimodal rack folder, but, in the root of multimodal rack.
Krish NAik: So you will see here, no ANV file, but if you open, then only you will see the .env file.
Krish NAik: We use copy-paste from local, no issues.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, can I proceed to the next one?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, the JINA API is required.
Krish NAik: Because I need a relanker, no? That's why.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I will assume that you guys have done the cloning. After the cloning, you have done a CD, multimodal rack. After that, you have, done git switch, the deployment branch.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, I will start working with the Docker Compose.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know, because we just need to run 3 commands, and I think we are out.
Krish NAik: Because this is actually how I'll be doing the deployment, so the Docker Compose setup, I have created it, but this setup is very specific to GPUs only.
Krish NAik: Okay, please let me know, can we start with the next part?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Please write it in the chat.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, there are…
Krish NAik: Till step 4, the idea is that you guys have created the .env file in the Lightning AI environment inside the multimodal rack folder. Now, first of all, I need to get Ulama, okay? So, let me just get ulama first of all.
Krish NAik: The idea is, during deployment.
Krish NAik: that Ulama will be in a separate container. Application will be in a separate container. Okay, quadrant will be in a separate container. Okay, that is the idea that we are taking. Later on, I'll be talking about that, but that's why you can actually look into the Docker Compose file. You will get a high-level idea if you know about Docker.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I will copy this.
Krish NAik: And let's get back to our write-down, okay? So here, I will just paste this command. See, what I've done? I have just opened, so, my Lightning AIDeploy.md file.
Krish NAik: Okay, and from there, step 5. Step 5 first command, which is the docker compose for your Ullama setup, that one, okay? So, I will just execute the command.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can see right now, in the system, Ulama is getting downloaded.
Krish NAik: This is a little bit microservice-based architecture.
Krish NAik: And, if you really want to look into the file, okay, so I'll be just showing you.
Krish NAik: Another failure.
Krish NAik: I think I didn't, lose it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is basically the Docker Compose file that I have. So, in this particular file, my application will be running separately, quadrant. So actually, like, if you want, you can actually look into this file. This is the core configuration that I have for multi-container setup.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, here I can see that the multimodal rag, okay, ULAMA is done. Okay, in a Docker instance, Ulama is running. In the next step, what I need.
Krish NAik: I need to get the OCR model. Okay, so let's get the OCR model. So the second command will actually do an ulama pull the OCR model into the ulama. So that's why docker compose hyphen M, okay, then I'm selecting the file, execute, ulama, and then inside that.
Krish NAik: So… let me just copy this one. So, right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the OCR model is getting downloaded.
Krish NAik: The 2.2 GB model.
Krish NAik: digest, I don't know, like, status, download a newer image of NVIDIA CUDA.
Krish NAik: No, really, I'm not sure about, like, I have to look into that.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that it should work fine.
Krish NAik: Please let me know for how many of you the first two command work, which you have in your, markdown file.
Krish NAik: Step 5, the first two commands.
Krish NAik: Okay, worked, worked, worked, alright, worked, great. Okay, so I can say that the OCR model is there.
Krish NAik: Now, you can do a confirmation by doing an OLAMA list inside the container. So, for that, I have this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you will see that, yes, the GLM OCR model, the 2.2 GB, is there. It means that, okay, I'm good to go with the next part.
Krish NAik: Check, first of all, you have a GPU or not route.
Krish NAik: If you don't have a GPU, really, you don't own, your system should have GPU.
Krish NAik: Do an NVIDIA-SMI and then check.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I can say that, fine, ULAMA setup is done, guys. Now, in the next step, I have to start the application.
Krish NAik: Okay, because my, quadrant and other things are pretty much ready, so let me get back to VSport.
Krish NAik: The file has to be there. Please change your branch.
Krish NAik: Please change your branch to deployment.
Krish NAik: Then you will get the files. In the master branch, those files are not there. Fine. Let's move ahead and let's start our full application.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the part where your application will start
Krish NAik: Okay, so everything will be loaded into the VRAM, so let's start. Okay, now see, guys, I'm moving to step 6 right now.
Krish NAik: Step 6, so let me just clear everything from here, okay?
Krish NAik: What happened? Okay, that shit. Okay, yeah.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me just paste this one. Docker compose hyphen M, the GPU YML file, which is a Docker Compose file, hyphen hyphen build. This will actually build the entire application.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is where main Docker build will be taking place. It will utilize my Docker file also, the actual Docker file, which I have, dockerfile.gpu. Okay, I'll just hit enter. It will take some time for the build. So first, you can see the quadrant.
Krish NAik: The quadrant is done, then in the next step, the Python, the application setup that is happening.
Krish NAik: Then the layout model torch, Torch vision came. This is for your GLM layout. All the necessary NVIDIA libraries are getting installed. You can see NVIDIA Quran, NVIDIA RTC, okay, so those things.
Krish NAik: Majorly, most of the things will come from Kache again.
Krish NAik: I cannot switch to a GPU.
Krish NAik: Why?
Krish NAik: So that's a single one-click option only to switch.
Krish NAik: Alright, wait, don't worry. Once I have done this, then I will look into your issue.
Krish NAik: Because in the UI, it comes as simple as that. You go and click on this one.
Krish NAik: like, once you have this option, here, switch to GPU. Just one click switch. So, really, I don't know what is going in your case, but really, like.
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: That is the easiest way, one-click switching instead.
Krish NAik: Alright, so exporting to image, exporting layers, I can see that, this part is working, okay?
Krish NAik: Let me remove the cat part, I don't think later on I need to execute some other part. I'll be just clearing this already. So, right now, my application has started. You can see that Quadrant is running.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: My quadrant started.
Krish NAik: Then,
Krish NAik: Okay, the visualizer part, really, I have not tested a visualizer, because my main focus will be right now the FastAPI application, but you will see that more logs are coming, Ulama app.
Krish NAik: app is your, FastAPI application. So, you will see a lot of startup logs right now.
Krish NAik: And fine, you have to wait for a few minutes.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the model will be loaded into the memory, so from here, in the other terminal, you can actually run, NVIDIA-SMI, you will see that how much
Krish NAik: like, RAM that is getting. Because right now, Ulama is taking some RAM, but slowly, slowly, this increase… this will actually increase more and more.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just wait, you have to really wait. This is a one-time thing.
Krish NAik: I need to load the models into VRAM. This process takes time.
Krish NAik: And right now, even, like, I have switched on flash attention. At least using flash attention makes it faster.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you will see that the application startup, those… that will come.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see right here, Application startup complete, UVCon 8000.
Krish NAik: Doc parser, parser is equal to OLAMA, backend is equal to GINA, collection is equal to Documents. Please let me know, okay, and again, if I try to run…
Krish NAik: What happened?
Krish NAik: Can you see the increase in VRAM? Previously, it was only 642MB. This time, how much?
Krish NAik: close to 8.6 GB, can I say that? It's being used?
Krish NAik: I just… that's why I'm showing you the stats also, guys.
Krish NAik: Please let me know how many of you see this, because my application has now started.
Krish NAik: I can see the logs. Application startup complete. UVCon running.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, can we proceed to the next part?
Krish NAik: Next part is application testing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I will be testing the application. Please be sure that… see, this startup takes time. You can take roughly around the application startup time is 2 minutes, 3 minutes.
Krish NAik: Okay, because that entire CPU to GPU uploading takes time.
Krish NAik: Alright, so now…
Krish NAik: Until this point, I think everybody has done, please tell me, then only I can move to the next part, for fast API application testing.
Krish NAik: on top of GPU.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's completed.
Krish NAik: Yes, the UVicon server started, okay, alright, fine. Now what I will do, I will go back to, this one, because I will be doing a port viewer operation, just like last time. From the right-hand side panel, you will see that there is a USB option, a port.
Krish NAik: The port viewer option. Please do have a check on this one. Can you see this port?
Krish NAik: port viewer option. Here, I'll be adding the ports. Two ports that I need, I'll be clicking on this option, and I'll be adding a new port, okay? So, let's add one for our,
Krish NAik: What?
Krish NAik: Fast API?
Krish NAik: Past API uses 8,000.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, then add another 4 for quadrant.
Krish NAik: Quadrant.
Krish NAik: Quadrant uses 6333.
Krish NAik: These two are the major configurations, so I have added the port. Now, what I will do, if I go to Quadrant.
Krish NAik: Okay? And you will see a public link option will be there.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, I can see that the written type, so copy the link, and paste it here.
Krish NAik: Can you see that you are getting, or you can open the dashboard also, just add slash dashboard.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, so this is my collections. Right now, no collections are there, fine.
Krish NAik: Because I have till now not created any collection, but the Quadrant service is fully up and running. How did you get that link?
Krish NAik: you have to come to your port viewer. Inside port viewer, I created the ports, no, for every port. Like, quadrant is running in which port, Fastipa is running in which port.
Krish NAik: So you have to just click on Quadrant, then you will get the public link.
Krish NAik: Similarly, the fast API link also, I'll be getting it.
Krish NAik: And both the links, the URL will be exactly the same. If I go to FastAPI.
Krish NAik: You can see, nothing here. Ensure that the app or server, fine, let me just copy, it takes time.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, slash docs.
Krish NAik: Can you see here? My Swagger UI also came?
Krish NAik: So I can say, yes, my Docker Compose setup was successful.
Krish NAik: I was actually planning for a visualizer also, because that part I've not done the complete testing yet. It's to be built in build-in phase, but the streamlin part, I've not added, but for visualization, I was actually
Krish NAik: thinking to add it. So, like, if you have more quotes, add that also. Something like this.
Krish NAik: 8501, if you have something running. In our case, I do have a Streamlit visualizer part, so that thing also I can simply
Krish NAik: Add it, you will see that if I click here on Streamlit, that visualizer file. But till now, I've not added the backend functionality, so it won't work. But you will see that, yes, the…
Krish NAik: core document will come, at least. Only the front end is there, the back-end connections are not me. Similarly, I hope
Krish NAik: It's making sense that I'm doing.
Krish NAik: I'm accessing each services that I have started using Docker Compose.
Krish NAik: It will come. Wait, wait. Okay? It will come. Give some time.
Krish NAik: 10, 20 seconds, give it. Okay, the fast API will start.
Krish NAik: here.
Krish NAik: like, health route and everything, I know it will work. Directly, I will start to work with the ingestion file. Okay, so if I try to make it dry.
Krish NAik: Choose a PDF, let me take the docklink one, 9 pages.
Krish NAik: String, let me remove it. Send empty value, false.
Krish NAik: True Executive.
Krish NAik: you will see that in the terminal, okay? So, this ingest file, initialization, embedding, OpenAI,
Krish NAik: HTTP guest, quadrant, initialized. Okay, now this will take time.
Krish NAik: You will see that, first of all.
Krish NAik: The model initialization, but the loading of the weights will be very, very fast.
Krish NAik: And actually, this time, you will see that, I can say that, more amount of previously 8GB,
Krish NAik: Okay, now you will see that this GPU usage will increase right now. You can look from here also, or from here also you can look from here.
Krish NAik: your, GPU uses VRAM. This also gives you. Can you see the peak?
Krish NAik: From where it went where? Previously, around 10GB. Now it is getting used close to 17GB GPU that is getting used.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yes, I know that GPU is getting used.
Krish NAik: It takes around 180 seconds, I feel, at around 3 minutes for the entire medium.
Krish NAik: Fast API for… how to tell, please, that Fast API should be coming. It takes time, probably 10 to 20 seconds delay can be there, but you will see the survival.
Krish NAik: Charan got it, able to load okay. Method still on Docker will finish today. Still on Docker. Okay, Docker is fine, but, then try to, add those ports through Port Weaver, and then try to access it. I think that it should work.
Krish NAik: It is, so, right.
Krish NAik: How do I upload the file? I think there is a direct upload option to PDF, Milint.
Krish NAik: I've also done the same thing, I've uploaded a PDF.
Krish NAik: If you see here, this is a PDF that I have uploaded.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is telling quadrant and fast ones.
Krish NAik: Okay, open them till the time you can't access them.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm showing you, even in GPUs, don't think that on GPU it will be, like, super fast. It's not like that. Okay, so here I can see parsing is done, at least faster than CPU, for sure. Okay, then coming the captioning part, OpenAI calls, I can see. Okay, then, coming the next part, which is…
Krish NAik: Upset, upset?
Krish NAik: upset to vector DB, collections, documents, alright, this is done. Wait, okay, so I can see upset at 37 points to documents, alright, I can say the ingestion is done. If I try to load the quadrant.
Krish NAik: So, this is Quadrant, which is blank. If I try to reload this page, you will see that it's coming now.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Everybody? So, the next part is asking the question.
Krish NAik: Ingestation is done, let's start working on generate.
Krish NAik: Okay, so similarly, let me remove the default one, filter modality, I don't need it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… top end, let me make it 5…
Krish NAik: And let me pass some questions.
Krish NAik: I think I had some questions previously, I have pasted a lot of questions.
Krish NAik: Let me start with the image.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me see execute.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I can see arrange the steps in OCR, table structure, OCR, layout, table structure, source project. So I can see that, yes, the response is coming.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… this part looks fine. No issues here. I can see the application is up and working, so this is actually deployed.
Krish NAik: If you really think about it, you have a public URL, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, let me just try to parse some more modalities and try to check it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so how much? Let me see. Because in some cases, yes, I know there can be a failure, till now I'm using GPT-4U. But, I can see the response, it's coming, page number 5,
Krish NAik: Okay, actual, so…
Krish NAik: 6.2, alright, this is working fine, let me change the question. And if you look into the results of the read anchor, I know the modality is table. I'm asking questions from table and images only, because that's my main focus. Text, I know it will work.
Krish NAik: So, let's try to change the question again, and try to pass something from our older page.
Krish NAik: So from here… Between the two CPUs, let me see if this one is working or not.
Krish NAik: which one is more efficient for Pipedia backend? The result should be Intel…
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, M3 Max with a peak of 2.56, which does not have it explicitly stated, okay, but I feel that here the results should be intentional, but I feel that, okay, in some case.
Krish NAik: This is wrong. With Lighting AI, how many pages PDF can you try? Pass any?
Krish NAik: If we want a bigger PDF, I can do that, guys. Let's take attention is all you need. Okay?
Krish NAik: Attention is all you need. This is GPU, so I'm a little bit free.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can take, these games now.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think attention is all you PDF already.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, okay, let me try to do an ingestion.
Krish NAik: Choose the PDF, let's go to downloads. I think attention paper that I have, attention paper, override,
Krish NAik: I don't need to overwrite 512 right now, okay?
Krish NAik: So, here you will see that previously this was 37, this number will increase.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I've given it, so you can actually look into the terminal. My next hit…
Krish NAik: So, this PDF has 15 pages right now, as you can see.
Krish NAik: This PDF has 15 pages. Okay, so again, it will take time… around 3 minutes, majorly.
Krish NAik: Okay, if I pass something like a longer one.
Krish NAik: Alright, this is 67 page, alright? So…
Krish NAik: Later on, because I know this is a long PDF, but let's see.
Krish NAik: How many of you are able to execute? Please let me know, because this is actually easy.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is asking how do you get the URL already told Mithaj from your port viewer option.
Krish NAik: Not able to upset Vayabi Shaykh?
Krish NAik: Because I feel this is a…
Krish NAik: Setup, and that setup should work for everyone.
Krish NAik: you have to pause and go slow, because pretty much I am done. I… all I was doing, the testing. Later on, then you guys can do the testing, then I can look into your tooling. Because it's…
Krish NAik: Only simple, like, I feel that 3 commands are there to set up your infra. Okay, so let's look into questions. Okay, like, how you guys are, facing the problem.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, Abhishek, raise your hand.
Krish NAik: Okay, yeah, yeah. So, where you got stuck? Like, Docker is not working, what is not working?
Abhishek: I mean, Docker and all, everything is working, it's just, I'm not able to ingest a document. Let me share my screen.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I will add you one, just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, just share your screen, you are in the panelist.
Krish NAik: Same keys.
Krish NAik: Balaji, same key, just like last time, we have done it in local.
Abhishek: Can you see my screen, hold on?
Krish NAik: Yes, I can see.
Abhishek: or this error, but then I changed it to OLAMA. Passer backend is OLAMA.
Abhishek: And I think I need to commit something, maybe what…
Krish NAik: Actually, EMV file is already there, then it should overwrite that.
Krish NAik: But again, like, doing changing here is not required, actually, if you have the ENV setup done.
Abhishek: I have this… okay, password. Okay, this needs to be changed.
Krish NAik: Yes, this has to be Olama, that's it.
Krish NAik: And check the GNRE ranker is working fine, then I think you'll be good to go.
Krish NAik: It's only the ENV file, you really don't need to touch the codebase also. You just have to be sure that the ENV file is correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, no, overwrite it, I think. In your case, you already created it. Overwrite, make it true. That option, false is there, no, make it true.
Krish NAik: And hit it. Let's see what happens.
Krish NAik: Wait, wait, wait, wait, tell me.
Krish NAik: This is your old log or your current log.
Abhishek: current job.
Krish NAik: That is… Because when I look into that one.
Abhishek: Including collection documents.
Abhishek: Upside to zero points.
Abhishek: Hmm.
Krish NAik: try to read the API, make it a split screen, because, like, instantly, Make it, like, 50-50%.
Krish NAik: No, no, that tab only just opened it. That tab just hung.
Krish NAik: I think, only I need the tab in this one. When you hit this one, exactly what that is coming, I need to check.
Abhishek: Do you… you…
Krish NAik: Both the tabs, 50-50, yeah.
Krish NAik: Yes, now hit. Let me see.
Krish NAik: Close the application. Close the application.
Krish NAik: Kill, kill, kill the application from your terminal, Ctrl-C, Ctrl-C, Ctrl-C.
Krish NAik: If you do changes, you have to stop, no. Again, how it will go. Again, the same commander on it, yes.
Abhishek: I thought that it's in your email.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, not like that, that's what…
Krish NAik: Nothing will change. Your public URL remains the same, so don't worry.
Krish NAik: Okay, just wait. It needs to be set up.
Krish NAik: That's why don't change the codebase. If you start changing the codebase, it becomes a problem. Only the ENV file that needs to be changed.
Krish NAik: Because, this is an cold start. In the cold start, I am actually loading all the models to VRAN.
Krish NAik: From the Port VR option, Rahul.
Krish NAik: the public URL we just showed, Abhisheh.
Krish NAik: How to get the public URL? Just click on the Port VR option.
Krish NAik: And then just click on Quadrant or Fast API, that's the only thing. We'll get the public link.
Krish NAik: Right now, your Docker is, your… it's warm… cold start is happening, so fine.
Krish NAik: Once you see the application startup in the logs, then it takes, I think, around 20 seconds, so just…
Abhishek: So, actually, I mean, if you have changed only environment size, right?
Abhishek: So, since it's a Docker, right? Defined docker.
Krish NAik: you can see your GPU usage in top L4 when it is written. You will see L4, L4, click on L4.
Krish NAik: It's picking up, so I know that We are doing right everything.
Krish NAik: That's why, actually, working with GPUs in production, you need to keep a track of all the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, slash docs, okay, it will come.
Krish NAik: I'm gonna try to hit the ingest API.
Krish NAik: Okay, and when the application started in the terminal, check that your backend is Ollama.
Krish NAik: It's… Because you can do that, but I always have a check from the terminal.
Krish NAik: Send empty value correct, recreate, make it true, because already, I think, last time we created it.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, so… fine.
Krish NAik: Now I can see that your hit, initializing, embedding, HTTP good, look, okay, this is fine.
Krish NAik: This is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, yeah, pull up my head.
Abhishek: Timothy.
Krish NAik: This is the detection model which is getting loaded right now.
Krish NAik: But you will see, now, again, GPU usage will increase once the OCR model is loaded.
Abhishek: Yep, good luck.
Abhishek: Yeah, I think this will work now.
Abhishek: Page count model for something.
Krish NAik: No, total PDF has 8 pages, so it's fine.
Krish NAik: That's why the NVIDIA stack, everything they provide, but actually using their infract, like, if somebody is a little bit good in this one, it's easy for them, that's why. Because you will see a lot of logs, but actually you have to figure it out, okay, for this particular container, this log is coming.
Abhishek: Nope.
Krish NAik: Just yet, I think… it takes around 3 minutes, you have to wait, 180 seconds.
Krish NAik: So, I have to generally, like, always try in this way. In one site, 50% split screen with your terminal, log 50% with your application, and that way it becomes easier.
Krish NAik: To exactly look at what is going on.
Krish NAik: Okay, GPU usage increased, it means the OCR is working right now, the OCR model.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, chunks got created, 37 chunks I can see right now, 37 embeddings that got created, upsetted.
Krish NAik: But the… where is the OpenAI call happened?
Krish NAik: OpenAI call was there, A little bit scroll over.
Krish NAik: OpenAI calls should be there, no?
Krish NAik: Scroll more above.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, yes, yes, I can see the opening costs, fine.
Krish NAik: Fine. Okay, now you can make a query.
Krish NAik: Click on generate, and pass, just like last time we uploaded, go to the generate one.
Krish NAik: Okay, remove the default system prompt and the filter modality, these two parameters not required.
Abhishek: Did you spring.
Krish NAik: Explain the dockling architecture. Anything, like, you can pass just for… Dockling architecture right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, and top and make it 5.
Krish NAik: No, no, top K, 20 is fact… top end, the re-ranker results, top 5.
Abhishek: if…
Krish NAik: Now hit.
Krish NAik: You will see the results version.
Krish NAik: Check your terminal also logs. You are getting yes.
Krish NAik: Doppler is designed with a modular? Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, coming.
Krish NAik: From there, okay? So, Dockling is designed similarly, like, you can look into.
Abhishek: Sure. Okay. Thanks. Thanks.
Krish NAik: Is it gonna explore already.
Abhishek: Thank you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so guys, for how many opioids up and working? Because this is an easier setup as compared to the CPU, a lot of things were there in our mind.
Krish NAik: Rahul?
Krish NAik: In your case, tell me, like, what till which point? Working for me? Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Yo, dead.
Rahul Parihar: Couple of things. Kenya, can I share my.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Krish NAik: Others, like, whoever want to share their screen, because this demo, I want in everybody's system to be up. Whoever is facing, just raise your hand.
Krish NAik: That is a way.
Krish NAik: Yes, I think. This was the main part of this.
Krish NAik: So, yes, if you have done it, I think you are good to go.
Rahul Parihar: So the first… first issue is… was on the local, and I have set up the GPU. So here it's saying dimension 3072 is not there, is less than equal to that.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rahul Parihar: Is the embedding model higher, or higher?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no. In your .env file, use text embeddings for embedding 3 small… what is the dimension? Till now in this course that you have learned?
Krish NAik: It's written in the comments also.
Rahul Parihar: Text embedding 3 small, yeah.
Krish NAik: Text embedding 3 small, does it support 3072?
Krish NAik: Text them large supports. You have to pass 1536. Please read the entire thing in government.
Krish NAik: Till the last point.
Rahul Parihar: Whoa.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Because this, I think, everybody should be by heart.
Krish NAik: that this model supports this dimension in this course, if you are working with RAD, dimensionality of embedding models.
Rahul Parihar: So, okay.
Rahul Parihar: Then the second is the GPU part. It is working.
Rahul Parihar: Till… let this be loaded.
Rahul Parihar: So, the issue that I'm having is over here, you know, like, in this part, I'm not…
Rahul Parihar: I'm not getting this part, so you have manually added the port for quality?
Krish NAik: is manually up to do, no? Your FastAP is running in 8000 port. So click on that, port sign.
Rahul Parihar: So, yeah, when I click on this, it says… This is not cool.
Krish NAik: That is fine, no, after that, of course, Swagger, you have to add slash docs.
Krish NAik: In the home route, I have added nothing, that's why you are getting not… Slash docs is…
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: Yes, Abhishek, with respect to caption generation, little bit, a structure that needs to be defined. I'll be talking about that in image captioning. Right now, even I have added it also, but I feel that I need to make it a little bit more robust.
Krish NAik: Because that is, somehow different.
Krish NAik: Because here, the entire game of table and images actually lies on there. Switch back and check your terminal logs.
Krish NAik: Yeah, totally.
Krish NAik: Okay, keep on looking into the logs. I can see that it's pretty much correct till now, till this one. Okay, so hurry.
Krish NAik: Nothing, vinom also raised your hand? Pundam?
Krish NAik: Are you able to share your screen?
Hari Kumar: Yeah, he is.
Hari Kumar: Can you add me into the panel?
Krish NAik: Yeah, I am adding, adding. Don't worry.
Krish NAik: Yes, Bono.
Rajat Khanna: Oh, boy!
Rahul Parihar: I recommend…
Krish NAik: Yeah, adapter.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, like, after completing all these assignments, we need to kill the session in the lightning as well, right?
Krish NAik: I'm just sharing my screen. You have to just sleep. Make a sleep operation, okay? You can see that, switch off studio, I'm just sharing that sleep. Look into my screen. Can you see my screen? Because he is also sharing, but look into mine.
Krish NAik: Are you… can you see my screen? Everybody, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, from here, see, what you have to do? Click on this machine, and can you see studio environment? You have to just switch off this. Done.
Krish NAik: Nothing more.
Krish NAik: for sleep, keep it in sleep mode. Otherwise, like, after this, you can delete also, but remember this one, okay? So once you have done this, yes, sleep. Done. Okay? You won't be charged anything.
Krish NAik: You will see entire data that you have worked, it will be automatically saved.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you want to rename, okay, you can rename this also for your later one. Okay, so please do that, everyone.
Krish NAik: Don't keep on using your GPU, because they are using credits.
Krish NAik: Alright, now I will stop sharing, and I will.
Rajat Khanna: I have a question, Paul, like, we are using, this, retrieval, like, in search, as well as in, the, gradient, like, there is, there are multiple options that we can pass. So, what are all other options, like, filter modality.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: combined. Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay. That's the thing already I told. Again, I'm repeating here. Filter modality is, like, whenever you are creating charts.
Krish NAik: Okay, I told you that for you, if you have an image, I'll be sending the caption, okay, and then based on that, that will be a text chunk. So you have to really identify, you know, which chunk is for what.
Krish NAik: So, one chunk is normal text, one chunk if you have images, then that chunk. So, that filter modality actually helps you. So, if you only want to look into the image chunks, okay, if somebody asks a question to your rag system, okay, explain me in Figure 1 what happened.
Krish NAik: So, for Figure 1, do you think that you really need to look into the entire PDF?
Krish NAik: In that case, you will be only looking into the image part, yes or no?
Rajat Khanna: Yes.
Krish NAik: That is the optimization, that's why I've added, for your own identification, that this chunk is for an image, this chunk is for a table.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, and just for a system-related question, so if we have a large amount of image data and large amount of text, data as well, or table data as well, so is it beneficial to have two separate, like, chunking strategies, or, like, vector DBs, for example, so the images are stored separately, and text are stored separately?
Krish NAik: See, don't need, but as… if you're telling… if you are really only working with images, in that case, I will go with Colpine.
Krish NAik: You have to understand that.
Rajat Khanna: No, no, yeah, interview perspective, like, they want to, like, design a system where you will be using multiple documents and all, and it should be less latency and less token needs to be.
Krish NAik: Now the question you have to ask, whether those documents will be having a lot of images, or a lot of text.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Always… see, whenever somebody asks a question, you have to ask the cross-question to get to that exact requirement. Otherwise, it will be a generic term. Whenever somebody asks you, you have to be very specific.
Krish NAik: If you ask that, okay, majorly, I'm only working with images, my document as majorly images, then I will not go with layout detection with OCR. I will go with the paradigmA, that's why. Entirely Kolpali.
Krish NAik: In that case, what will happen? Yes, my embeddings will be there, but for scaling, I can apply quantization on top of the embeddings, which will actually help me to scale.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay. In that way. And the other question that you asked, what was that system prompt? So generally, whenever you are generating in drag, you know that during the generation, you send a prompt.
Rajat Khanna: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now I have given that prompt, if you want to pass your custom prompt, and overwrite the default prompt which is available in generate.py.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay. And, yeah, just on a curiosity aspect, for example, like, we have only one PDF which includes only images, okay? And there will be one PDF which will be only including table and text, okay? So now, can we do only images? Like, we are asking questions related to only images.
Rajat Khanna: So, we will not want to go through all the process, like, we can store, like, images in the separate vector DB, and the tables and the text in separate vector DB, and code is written like that, if the question is related to image and so, just target this retrieval strategy, which will be getting, retrieval from the image vector DB, and if the question is other aspect, then it will target the other retrieval strategy, which only goes
Rajat Khanna: for the table and text. Is that a possible thing?
Krish NAik: Yes, it is possible, see, if you want to save your images in a separate collection, if you want to save your cables in a separate collection, that is also fine, I have no issues. But right now, I feel that if you have everything in a single document, then it doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: to your chunking strategy, because whenever you are doing a structured lever chunking, there is a cross-linkage across your chunks. That breaks.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, got it, got it, okay.
Rajat Khanna: Got it.
Krish NAik: Okay, but if you feel that, okay, continuously, if you have 100 images, fine. Then, in that case, use a separate collection. But generally, if you have, like, these type of academic papers, technical documents, where you have tables and other things, formulas and other stuff, okay, handwritten, then I feel that if you have a mixture, take this approach.
Rajat Khanna: Yesterday, yeah, yesterday, one interviewer asked me, like, if you're building a system in which the user will be uploading unappropriate data as well, like unappropriate images, as well as some restricted, text as well.
Rajat Khanna: So how you will be bifurcating, like, those images and those texts should not be entered into a final system and should not be a part of the production.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, now, see, if somebody is asking such question, it means that somebody has uploaded an inappropriate image, okay?
Rajat Khanna: Correct, correct.
Krish NAik: Generally, in that case, like, if you want, I can go with an NSFW model, not safe for work, something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I will say that, okay, and I will tag it.
Krish NAik: If… it's just like an image classification in simple terms.
Rajat Khanna: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, I can do that, and then only I can proceed. So, there are NSFW models not safe for work, so you can actually run on top of that. Similarly, like, another question come, if you have somebody have, confidential information, in that you have to do pie masking, pi redact.
Krish NAik: So, anyone you upload, like, this is my credit card number, generally in finances, account, credit card number, okay, do account details, you can actually do a simple masking.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay.
Krish NAik: There's a little bit as far as from security perspective, that's all.
Rajat Khanna: Yes, and I was also thinking about, like, we will be applying some guardrails in that, that same, in that guardrail will be, we will be having another model, we'll be checking on that, okay, this is allowed, and this is not allowed.
Krish NAik: Now, guardrails, where you want to apply. There are multiple ways you want to apply on top of the LLM output.
Krish NAik: No.
Rajat Khanna: guardrails, like, while someone is uploading his text, and after, like, it will be storing into the, our DB, before storing it, there will be a guardrail, and also, like, retrieval, and the information that will be shown on the output system, that is a separate guardrail. I'm just putting a guardrail before the information enters into the system.
Krish NAik: That is pretty much query validation, we call it.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, quit, okay.
Krish NAik: Because if somebody's asking that, then you are doing the validation, no?
Krish NAik: No, no, I…
Rajat Khanna: Information, like, for example, like, you are entering this PDF, okay? Attention, all you need, or something like that. But, for example, like, someone is adding a PDF document, which is inappropriate, like, for adult content is there, or, like, unappropriate images are there.
Rajat Khanna: So, you don't want that images to enter into your system, or save into your.
Krish NAik: what I don't know. So, first of all, if you apply a layout detection model, then actually you have the image bounding boxes. Then you can pass that to a classification model, and then simply you can say that, okay, this is NSFW, rest of the operation block.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. Oh. Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Paul, the document is now uploaded, and it is showing, so…
Rahul Parihar: Why, if I'm just giving a… testing it, giving the number of thread in the budget?
Rahul Parihar: It says, file not found.
Rahul Parihar: The given thread budget is not there, it's just the same document, you know?
Krish NAik: Leave that path, first of all.
Rahul Parihar: So, till here, this is the GPU one, you know?
Rahul Parihar: I'm still testing the local one.
Krish NAik: what do you anemic,
Krish NAik: You are not getting the answer from the retrieval teams.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah… So…
Krish NAik: Because ask… just ask a simple question, explain the dockling architecture, let me see.
Krish NAik: Collection is equal to string it's written.
Krish NAik: Our collection is document, so, so, this is the ingest part.
Krish NAik: seat.
Rahul Parihar: search.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay. No, no, no, search, lip search, lip search, go to generate.
Krish NAik: Go to Generate.
Rahul Parihar: It is generated, okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, now click on try it out. Okay, now pass the question that you want to pass.
Krish NAik: create a budget, in Apple.
Rahul Parihar: In Apple Tree.
Krish NAik: Fine, fine, just keep this query only. Make top, n is equal to 5.
Krish NAik: N, then, n, then.
Krish NAik: Remove the filter modality.
Krish NAik: Just, okay, remove the system prompt string.
Krish NAik: That parameter not required. Okay, now, hit.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Rahul Parihar: And mine.
Krish NAik: Now, I can see that at least… this is fine, this is because of the captioning part, but I can see that the re-anchor is returning characterism, so I know that that particular thing is correct.
Rahul Parihar: And on local, if I've… why I'm facing an issue that even if I'm changing
Rahul Parihar: The embedding image too small, saving it.
Rahul Parihar: But still, it was taking the older value, so it's the .en ENV is not getting loaded.
Rahul Parihar: Is that the problem? On the local?
Krish NAik: This I cannot say, it's just system… otherwise, update, check the config.py.
Krish NAik: manually hard-code it if it is not working. Generally.
Krish NAik: everything, that's why, because that is the other way around. By this time, like, hard-coded, or it should be available through your .env. These two are the major options. Praveen, you have raised your hand. I think Punam also.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Are you gonna start sharing this? Is this a casual thing, or, like, you know, I can,
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: I'll be the last person to talk, like, you know, I can meet up.
Krish NAik: He'll go.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Thanks, dude.
Krish NAik: frame. Yeah.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, how are you structuring this? Punam?
Krish NAik: Hari, no audio from your side.
Hari Kumar: Height, currently, I'm good with lightening.ai, so I could see responses. I don't have any issue.
Hari Kumar: The thing is, when I'm running it locally, right, I can see…
Hari Kumar: The server is running, but when I'm trying to open the server, right, it is not, this connection error is showing.
Krish NAik: Make it localized.
Krish NAik: Local host, local host, 000…
Hari Kumar: Oh.
Krish NAik: This is Windows.
Krish NAik: Because I thought, see, by this time in the course, You shouldn't know this.
Hari Kumar: I missed it, okay.
Krish NAik: That's why this is where, like, your main developer thinks that comes up.
Poonam Nanda: Hi, Paul, am I audible?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Poonam Nanda: So for me, the GPU thing is working, but the one that I was trying in the local, and I just told also in the chat, right, that it's giving that error for delay.
Krish NAik: Alright, alright, you share, because for the model installation, but adjust to it, I will add you to panelist.
Krish NAik: Others, please do this, because, then, tomorrow, at least you know that this will be our deployment setup also.
Krish NAik: Okay, because we'll be using Farget.
Krish NAik: Okay, with ECS, with EFS, that's how. Can we clean up Lightning AI environment? Yes, Melinda, if you want, delete the studio. Delete the entire studio.
Krish NAik: Because, you know, the setup that I have done, it's just 3 minutes. Switch on the studio, get clone, and then Docker commands done. So anytime you can do it.
Rahul Parihar: So, when are we supposed to use the inject… injects file is, fine, you upload the document, but.
Krish NAik: That is for local path, generally for local mode.
Krish NAik: That is 5 by a path. It is not required, actually, I will remove that one.
Krish NAik: It is in local system. If you are working, then you can directly pass the system path.
Poonam Nanda: Paul, let me know if my screen is visible.
Krish NAik: Yes, it is visible.
Poonam Nanda: Yeah, so, in the local, whenever I'm trying, I'm getting this, tripip install.
Krish NAik: Go back to Terminal, go back to terminal.
Poonam Nanda: Right? Okay.
Krish NAik: terminal.
Poonam Nanda: I'll kill this for now.
Krish NAik: drop the application.
Poonam Nanda: stopped.
Krish NAik: Now, what is the command?
Poonam Nanda: I did the pip install King… I did this.
Krish NAik: Are you using UV?
Poonam Nanda: I tried with UV also.
Krish NAik: Hmm? You know, what is…
Poonam Nanda: Great menu options.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay. Okay, okay, alright, this package is… Actually, in Windows,
Krish NAik: Windows really, because this model, if it is installed, it's telling it's not getting detected there. Text2SQL RAG is your environment.
Poonam Nanda: this…
Krish NAik: Alright, so in that case, you'll be provincial if you have done it.
Krish NAik: Whoa… Alright, go back, show me that log.
Krish NAik: Okay, you are not getting a… no, start the application once.
Poonam Nanda: Okay, yeah, sorry.
Krish NAik: That's tragic.
Krish NAik: Because here it's telling no module named Torch.
Poonam Nanda: Yes, so even I tried uninstalling, installing Torch as well.
Poonam Nanda: Nothing is working.
Krish NAik: Alright, just, don't use that script, serve.py, use the actual application server.
Poonam Nanda: Okay, so can you tell me…
Krish NAik: No, no, the command will be there only, no. Open your testing.md, go to section 2,
Krish NAik: You know, first of all, close that, initializer.
Krish NAik: Mmm.
Krish NAik: Windows is, should work. I don't feel there should be any issues.
Krish NAik: Because it's sagging phase modulum.
Krish NAik: Markdown review, below, below, below, below, below.
Poonam Nanda: Okay, this window is coming, the share window.
Krish NAik: Cool.
Poonam Nanda: able to hide this.
Poonam Nanda: Yes.
Poonam Nanda: some broader one, which is coming for me. Okay, anyways…
Krish NAik: I can…
Poonam Nanda: C like this also, right?
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Poonam Nanda: Checked.
Krish NAik: Go below, go, below, go.
Krish NAik: Below, below, below, these are all scripts. Below, below, below, below, below, below.
Krish NAik: Below, below, below, below, below, below. Section 2.
Krish NAik: Okay, and now… Okay, the reload command, yes, that one, line number 10306.
Poonam Nanda: 306, okay.
Krish NAik: We'll be this one.
Poonam Nanda: This was also one thing I was getting dock past, so then I tried with that one.
Krish NAik: Perfect. First of all, deactivate your environment.
Poonam Nanda: Okay.
Krish NAik: Create a new environment for this project.
Poonam Nanda: Sure, okay. Let me try that in that case, you can take others, and I'll just try that one and sync up. Okay.
Krish NAik: And I think anybody is nobody else's risk.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Poonam Nanda: Then great, I'll try that one now, because otherwise…
Krish NAik: The new one is okay.
Poonam Nanda: for me.
Krish NAik: create a new environment, do the installation, okay, because I think it will work, it's because… because when you do that, UVSync.
Krish NAik: Because in your case, you can do an ubiq already, I've given the 2ML file, or otherwise manually create the environment, then do ubpip install, .dev, in that way, look into the 2ML file. All the requirements are there, so I feel that it should work. There should not be an issue.
Poonam Nanda: Okay. I'll try with a fresh environment.
Poonam Nanda: Thank you.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think no more hands are ready. So, guys, how many of you have really done it on the GPUs, at least? Tell me. The GPU part was really, I failed.
Krish NAik: it was easier as compared to the CPU things, but really, like, do the development in CPU and then move to GPU, it becomes easier.
Krish NAik: So, at least whoever has not done, please go through the video and at least do it. Because this becomes our base. Then the deployment to AWS, then I can say the architecture will be a bit different.
Krish NAik: But the core functionalities, we have already gone through. Now, little bit, that image captioning part,
Krish NAik: I'll be upgrading it a little bit better, because I feel that that is somehow, again, a bottleneck. Changing model is one option, but again, let me see, like, getting some other structure today.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Praveen, I think now you can go ahead. Nobody has raised their hands.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Oh, holy, yeah.
Krish NAik: Will you get it wrong?
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Correct.
Krish NAik: Here.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Yeah, Paul, like, I just wanted to share that, recently I have secured a job with, one of the investment banker companies.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: So it's been, I would say, 5 months that I got laid off, with the company that I was working, and your RAC course and LLM content has been a big part of my energy, Paul, like, you know, I have learned a lot of
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: things from you, and I really wanted to appreciate, you know, your efforts on whatsoever. You wanted to, you know, the way you were putting all these, you know, helped me, and I really wanted to thank you for, like.
Krish NAik: Because, see, now is a good time to mainly make a switches, really, and others also are currently in the interview process. This is a good time, at least. Many products, Fortune 200 companies are actually hiring a lot.
Krish NAik: Everyone… the requirement of RAG in the Indian market is really high, because LLM engineering and others, very less, they do it in India.
Krish NAik: even productivist organizations, I'm saying they are doing it very, very less, but that's the idea, because from here, the idea is to now push yourself to something much more.
Krish NAik: Because that's what I'm planning, I think, next week I'll be sharing, even the new syllabus, I think 50-60% is done, 40% is remaining.
Krish NAik: But I'll be sharing, because that is the real gold one that I can say. Okay, but…
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Thanks, Paul, like, I'm from US, though. Yeah, as I said, like, US market was pretty bad, from past few months, I would say. No, it might be picking up, but,
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: I would say your course was the, I would say, key point for me to crack any… I think I have secured, like, two more jobs too, but they're gonna tell me on this Monday.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: But still, like, whatsoever, I would say, at least, I have learned more than 80% of the things that the current market is asking, right? This rag and everything, that I learned from your course on you, Paul, like,
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: I can't thank you more than enough.
Krish NAik: Yeah. You're welcome, and we will continue learning, because this is.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Oh, yeah, yeah, of course.
Krish NAik: No pick.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Yeah, I'll be following you forever, like, you just made me, you know.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, because even I have plans, like, for U.S. students only, I'm planning to launch the badge. That's why. So, I think you will be getting a mail also from Kresh. There will be a separate meeting only for U.S.
Krish NAik: students, so we have selected, I think around total, we have around 2,000 base of students, Canada, US, Mexico, that region, so everyone will be dropping mail. And based on your time zone only, we'll be launching the next one. I will be only taking that.
Krish NAik: a little bit ironic.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Olympic bus.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: So, I think everyone please do this, at least, okay, because I… next week, we'll be working on AWS deployment, but at least from the code perspective, I will start the discussion a little bit, because I feel that the core setup is done, most of you are now familiar.
Krish NAik: Well, I can say that it's pretty much like the same project, but only the thing changes in the deployment, because first time I'm using Docker Compose, multi-container setup.
Krish NAik: But again, I feel that it is not so much hard. If you guys have not known about, little bit, I'll be talking about Docker Compose tomorrow, and then coming to the core code baseline.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine then. I think, we can log off. Bye-bye, everyone.
Krish NAik: Thanks for joining.
Rahul Parihar: Thank you, Paul. Thank you very much.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Thanks.